<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="published"
    langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid url="http://library.duke.edu/rubenstein/findingaids/adfadfrecords/">adfadfrecords</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the American Dance Festival Records, circa 1924-1985, bulk 1934-1977
            <num>ADF.015</num></titleproper>
        <author>ADF Archives Staff, Dean Jeffrey</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>American Dance Festival Archives</publisher>
        <p><date>2008</date></p>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-08-22 11:55:53
          -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>English</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date>2014</date>
        <item>Converted from dtd to schema and transformed with AT-import-fixer.xsl</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <repository>
        <corpname>American Dance Festival Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>American Dance Festival records</unittitle>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname source="ingest">American Dance Festival</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>ADF.015</unitid>
      <physdesc altrender="whole">
        <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">89.05 Linear Feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1988" type="inclusive">circa 1924-1988, bulk 1934-1977</unitdate>
      <langmaterial id="aspace_3a42a5054766fab1678d1885ed21ca27">Material in English</langmaterial>
      <physloc id="aspace_9a11efb72cd71f92c60b8b33e2c7b114">For current information on the location
        of these materials, please consult the ADF Archives.</physloc>
      <abstract id="aspace_a9ba2dd1d7694d341aefad381e673eb4">The American Dance Festival is a
        non-profit organization committed to serving the needs of dance, dancers, choreographers,
        and professionals in dance-related fields. It presents a summer festival of modern dance
        performances and educational programs, hosts community outreach activities, and sponsors
        numerous projects in the humanities. Its mission is to create and present new dance works,
        preserve the modern dance heritage, build wider national and international audiences and
        enhance public understanding and appreciation for modern dance, and provide training and
        education for dancers and choreographers. Contains correspondence, lists, administrative
        materials, memoranda, contracts, legal documents, financial records, class schedules,
        teaching materials, student records, clippings, press releases, publicity materials,
        brochures, tickets, posters, and other printed materials created by or related to the
        American Dance Festival.</abstract>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_2186c6a06a1ec2d13fd0d1cf106e21c8">
      <head>Access Restrictions</head>
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
      <p>Please contact the American Dance Festival Archives (adf@americandancefestival.org) to
        arrange for use of these materials.</p>
      <p>Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this
        collection.</p>
      <p>In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, the
        American Dance Festival Archives permits students to inspect their education records and
        limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.</p>
      <p>Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where
        individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_04ebd786e7190b84ee7e9d8b871cee1e">
      <head>Copyright Notice</head>
      <p>Copyright for official American Dance Festival administrative records is held by the
        American Dance Festival; all other copyright is retained by the authors of items in these
        papers, or their descendants, as stipulated by United States copyright law.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite id="aspace_9cd2e46f63b74b623b2169a1388c3561">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>[Identification of item], American Dance Festival Records, American Dance Festival
        Archives.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_7165a4f8c0683b3a5c7cdb4c488ded8c">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Processed by ADF Archives Staff, Oct. 2004</p>
      <p> Encoded by Dean Jeffrey, Nov. 2008</p>
      <p> Accessions were merged into one collection, described in this finding aid.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <bioghist id="aspace_d801c3de3aacdd455160865a3ca5f3a6">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>The American Dance Festival is a non-profit organization committed to serving the needs of
        dance, dancers, choreographers, and professionals in dance-related fields. It presents a
        summer festival of modern dance performances and educational programs, hosts community
        outreach activities, and sponsors numerous projects in the humanities. Its mission is to
        create and present new dance works, preserve the modern dance heritage, build wider national
        and international audiences and enhance public understanding and appreciation for modern
        dance, and provide training and education for dancers and choreographers.</p>
      <p>The American Dance Festival traces its origins to the Bennington School of Dance, founded
        in 1934 in Bennington, Vermont by several notable figures in the emerging art of modern
        dance: Martha Graham, Hanya Holm, Doris Humphrey, and Charles Weidman. The school, led by
        Martha Hill, allowed choreographers to experiment and teach dance techniques. A performance
        series, held in conjunction with the school, provided the choreographers with opportunities
        to present their newly created works. For one season, in 1939, the festival was held at
        Mills College in Oakland, California, but returned to Bennington the following year.
        Beginning in 1948, the festival was held at Connecticut College, and in 1977, the decision
        was made to move it to Duke University in Durham, North Carolina.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_fdc98578db49ec38ab89d4cf63a9d560">
      <head>Collection Overview</head>
      <p>Contains correspondence, lists, administrative materials, memoranda, contracts, legal
        documents, financial records, class schedules, teaching materials, student records,
        clippings, press releases, publicity materials, brochures, tickets, posters, and other
        printed materials created by or related to the American Dance Festival before the decision
        to move to Durham, North Carolina, in the fall of 1977.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <subject source="lcnaf">Choreography -- United States.</subject>
      <subject source="lcnaf">Dance -- United States.</subject>
      <subject source="lcnaf">Modern Dance -- United States.</subject>
      <corpname source="lcnaf">American Dance Festival.</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Bennington School of the Dance.</corpname>
      <corpname source="lcnaf">Connecticut College American Dance Festival.</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc>
      <c01 id="aspace_7697d0cd09c6220ac9eee71a091fe088" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Administration, circa 1924-1981</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_6ddf52a40aca7008ee0671adb4ad6291" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>ADF Store and Merchandise, 1962-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_2572d1fa43a57697902c49ff3bae4ad4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_6e9057410130bdc5ef63092fee424b5f">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, inventory lists, tee-shirt designs, order forms, and
              administrative papers related to the sale of merchandise during the festival and the
              management of the store at the theater and summer offices.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_af6deeaf4ce39cde77aea423d1be8204" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Administrative Assistant, 1958-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_6d1100cfc34240cae92bb6eccfcf0cd1" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <arrangement id="aspace_17b065ee3fb485d21ac02e2e48ac0781">
            <head>Arrangement</head>
            <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </arrangement>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_0a1c1105ec604bcb3d469b4550c9038b">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains administrative materials, correspondence, form letters, memoranda, mailing
              lists, mailings information, and listings of secretarial duties. In the 1960s,
              administrative assistants were secretaries working directly under the director. In
              later years, as the festival's administration became more complex, multiple
              administrative assistants were added and their duties were expanded beyond
              secretaries. Assistants included:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
              <item>Constance Carney, 1958</item>
              <item>Olive Hersant, 1963-1966</item>
              <item>Faith Gulick, 1964-1965</item>
              <item>Marjorie Chapman, 1967-1971</item>
              <item>Kay McGrath, 1971</item>
            </list>
            <p>Also included are files for Lisa Booth, Assistant to Charles Reinhart in New York,
              1972-1977.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_c60090e8969b0294c250b8d0da8e4266" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Administrative Director, 1969-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">20
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_4aac8c8aad56b34e4a77ba6903421cda" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_16fc26cbe417d9c3b09f2e71d43dc744">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains administrative materials, correspondence, form letters, meeting notes and
              transcripts, newspaper clippings, drafts, messages, short notes, and memos, signed
              petitions, staff handbook, brochures, press releases, and a listing of statistics.
              Materials contain correspondence and documents written to and from the Administrative
              Director and the Administrative Assistant and the Director's office concerning daily
              activities, responsibilities and instructions as well as personal notes.
              Administrative director was a staff position from 1969 to 1993. Beginning in 1969,
              Charles Reinhart's first year as Director, an administrative director, a coordinator,
              an administrator, or an operations manager worked with Charles Reinhart and Martha
              Myers, the Dean, to coordinate the workings of ADF's school and festival. The
              Administrative Directors were:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
              <item>Robert Hale and C. Fred Grimsey (Administrators), 1969</item>
              <item>Olive Johns (Administrator), 1970</item>
              <item>Kay McGrath (Administrator), 1971-1973</item>
              <item>Ceilia Halstead and Cordette Grimsey (Coordinators), 1974-1975</item>
              <item>Mary Jane Inram and Lisa Booth (Administrators), 1976</item>
              <item>Lisa Booth (Administrative Director), 1977-1980</item>
            </list>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_1c14dcfc43f744db7fdecd86496e3595" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Archives, 1948-1978 and undated</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.41 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_378df7f2d18824f2bf0993225968c8cb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_6d4dc5a4b803c547da666e97d4108be9">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, donation acknowledgements, form letters, sales notices,
              administrative materials, notes and memoranda, identification cards, rental
              agreements, photograph schedules, telegrams, ADF archives inventories, and a file
              storage survey of ADF files at Connecticut College, documenting ADF archival
              activities (except Labanotation and the Film Notation project), even when there was no
              formal archives program. Also included is correspondence between ADF and other
              institutions, such as the New York Performing Arts Library, regarding requests for ADF
              materials for other dance collections. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_cc0be976e3508d159e8e324c4e90dbc4" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Documentation, 1949-1974 and undated</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_302c481ad2f73a039a23bb3882fadccf" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_57d3d16951c78c958ad390c1948f9700">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains information and correspondence about photographers and videographers who
                actively documented ADF activities, with the exception of personnel related
                information, such as hiring and firing correspondence. It also includes release
                forms and information and transcripts of oral histories. The oral histories include
                a 1959 group interview on the subject of the first year at Bennington with several
                people including the Limons, the Lloyds, Louis Horst, and Bessie Schonberg. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_4e356f21f2927fdbc71471d57fdb341c" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Interview Notes: Martha Hill</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_445733658a0ff14f67e458780fc9b0d5" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_42f6cc66048fcc91a38b3b6eb30352d4" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Interview Notes: Sophie Maslow</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_d3c061dc310b46c33c92a5c0b3c91853" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_c9f57d777889efbf823501a67ee9836f" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Interview Notes: Jeanette Schlottman Roosevelt</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_82512aa79f76c45dae6702fb5c0feca2" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_d2454d4a44db0b1f3ce68a3eb8926ff1" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Interview Notes: Theodora Wiesner</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_0e637806c7a4dd877ad67d55e273c017" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_f916205fe97190dbbd589701437e45cc" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Oral History: First Year at Bennington, July 1959</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_61806dd371a2370e5dba7293c28e68f3" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_c22bcd5980efd3940264c2dd47414bf2" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Photographer, 1949-1974</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_c431eb325a627a0488359e3212858d0d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_7cf92ee27ee115cef62d896c63908807" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Historical Facts, 1948-1966</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_4e5c58fdaf08765295165e1eb5160e8c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_792cead2a77dfd4781da671e4306e83b">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains information compiled by various ADF staff to document important ongoing
                events in ADF history such as premieres and commissions.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_59110f4e5f706475385dbc9943fc89ee" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>American Dance Festival Premieres, 1948-1966</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_c350f03fe2e5b4768cd3cbf2e032b1fd" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_3a0b9a75d72c30ccac08a9259c729917" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Preservation, 1953-1978</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_c397227eea44c77cfc0095b044e73faa" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e95c2bd20c1babaf064cd7a588d1a5b3">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains materials concerning the administration and preservation of the
                collection. Some correspondence concerns other repositories collecting ADF
                materials. Includes correspondence with other dance collection repositories, such as
                NYPL and Ohio State University, regarding the reproduction of films resulting from
                the Film and Notation Project for their own collections. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_8d16e5747a7e7ee303b908a7f7f4b65f" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Preservation, 1953-1962</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_e8cb63cd1967375ca50b980d79c73b5f" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_7b1f6cde01669e247f68fc18bc8a399e" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Preservation, 1966-1973</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_6da0295c468783fc9e0b5a8dbfd5566d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_e2cac573191af086d7264ef94ba4e435" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Preservation, Doris Humphrey Costume, 1970-1971</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_975a1f9d43a10aa2d31d3c06f76b8e72" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_1aab5d230838da0f8eeeb9db57d8f62e" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Preservation, Records at Connecticut, 1976-1978</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_14f1a5410026cff4615a50281509cfe2" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">1</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d9c7c8e561a8d1ee98d45ade4b899be7" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Usage, 1956-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_ec4db642e33346cabff2a1fbd8d27b97" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_2cab84413491bafa36583e85c2a77e0d">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains materials concerning reference services by the ADF Archives and use of
                archival documents. Consists primarily of correspondence between archivists and
                patrons, even before ADF had an archival program. Also includes forms and
                correspondence regarding film rentals for choreographic reconstruction (circa
                1965-1969). </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d2e56c2a76c85c7b006ac0e62742c5b0" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bennington College and Mills College, 1934-1942</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_5fd45f60c7f7351648f8bfca4f322ede" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_28d1c8ddeb8b23fbf7960a422af9fbbc">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence and notes from annual reports including schedules, program
              information, and general summaries that document ADF's working relationship with
              Bennington College and Mills College as host institutions. Also includes research
              notes from various sources detailing information about the School of the Dance from
              1934 to 1942. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_444ca098b6f7bbbe638d99153c94fc33" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Board of Directors, 1975-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_4640a05db1444ddfb2072be04717fa81" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_a875139a47bd61cd32d21f9222d0d46e">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains meeting minutes and correspondence related to the American Dance Festival
              Board of Directors, including correspondence from Charles Reinhart inviting Betty Ford
              to become the Honorary Chairman of the Board of Directors. The Board of Directors was
              established during the first meeting of the incorporators of the American Dance
              Festival, Inc. on July 31, 1975. Charles L. Reinhart, Martha Myers, and Elizabeth
              Booth were nominated and elected by the incorporators. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d928976ea652757a55c9da8a09d2905e" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Box Office, 1948-1977 and undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_1cc387f76c319fec07b2136be933bdb5" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">1</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_9115dc8537791462fcf937e56d110cf6" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Complementary tickets, 1949-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">22
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_55ee2462298b89e44060bf07c03c9caf" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_f4635de2ade826b82fa7592b5f45384c">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains lists of people, including critics and VIPs, issued complementary tickets.
                Also includes administrative correspondence and notes, along with correspondence to
                and from those who were issued tickets, as well as form letters regarding festival
                schedules, form letters outlining complementary ticket policy, and faculty, staff,
                and student ticket sign-up sheets. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_bc348da58c1c87e540169ed0deb5f6b7" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Group Sales, 1962-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_b8e11aa781e55c72b8753868e3e5bb2b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">1</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_f3239c2bd9d2c4f5639c100d0a80c8b7">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, form letters, and festival scheduling information
                regarding group ticket sales, which were primarily discounted sales to businesses
                and non-profit organizations. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_80022311c432242af7a41c5a17f0e753" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>House, 1948-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">28
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_3f1d10c38c05f7ee1c0a77cb6947a2b2" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_98d36481a064b781d3c43197a680d760">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains seating charts and pricing information, administrative materials,
                correspondence, usher and ticket taker lists, usher information sheets, application
                forms, box office schedules, box office summaries, complementary ticket sign-up
                sheets, concessions information, form letters, and payment and expenses information. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_bb3cae580a4cfd86e51308f325b301e1" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Interns, 1967</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_23ad4aba15fea6e8e59d1570cd3f7777" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_d4d737e9329d16dda424af93f96b4331">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains payroll and scheduling information pertaining to the box office
                internship.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_cb4a1a4a70a185a36d93ca8aaa877a2b" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Manager, 1948-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">28
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_2970f11c81dd3a55097e7b94cb92e7b2" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c0fb31f7bb2e4618de7800274a8bc277">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, memos, form letters, administrative materials, ticket
                policy information, schedules, subscriber and single ticket requests and payment
                materials, ticket samples, seating plans and pricing information, ticket order
                forms, ticket sales locations, complementary ticket policy forms, discounted ticket
                information, box officer managers' final reports, budget information, box office
                manager application information, hotel information, and Ticketron contract
                materials. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c7ac1308c4ad5aa45b358de9106a4819" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Reports, 1949-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">33
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_6738671eb4c7dc542e61ee29df1e5c22" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_f7608c07a29c4080224b1a37c0d965c6">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains box office reports, administrative materials, seating charts, receipts,
                and correspondence. Includes information such as the number of tickets sold for each
                seating price for each show and the gross and net income of each performance.
                Correspondence includes box office policies, estimates of profits, and ticket
                returns. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_b09512175c09d145a4382cddc84abd2a" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Single tickets, 1963-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_af4390b089f90e3de4a96a1c8c5ce73c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_3a25f7341c1c5b8abefa0c06600d3084">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, forms, subscription forms, student and faculty lists,
                listings of ticket purchases, and administrative materials concerning single ticket
                sales and buyers. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ea31ba1aed3f57228d3331a81ac56ec0" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Subscriptions, 1962-1976</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_c2fbf475b64d75996174886b0770f87e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ed231e98ad822f2e8eaa2bc49648d3f2">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence to and from subscribers, printed items, seating charts,
                forms, and administrative materials concerning subscriptions and subscribers. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_680e2ba3b962523701d4b04fb5b5711a" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Ticket Forms and Brochures, 1949-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">30
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_791150cd7a2eec3a50d4da70f5fda36d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_c05b67fdd48df1a1092c43a3ad4b769a">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains ticket order forms, event notices, and season brochures. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ec801b5b899016996263d973acbe2b02" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Tickets, 1955-1977 and undated</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_9ab307bd90ff6a1c6adcda76d941ddab" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e47d1aaafc505ea0d6be42c46901c31c">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains performance tickets. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_7528b77bb155177e1b2f10bf153dcb2d" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Community Development and Public Affairs, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_cbfd7ab0521b34da1ac01c89a8bae07f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_64b7e7f7d9051188434b2fbdc67dae46">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains materials on a variety of projects that involved bringing dance and other
              arts programs to the public, including contacts with government officials and arts
              patrons in attempts to find and continue support for dance and the arts. Also includes
              materials regarding classes held at Connecticut College that were open to
              non-Connecticut College students, such as the Folk and Square Dance class, offered
              during the summer festival, and children's modern dance classes and adult elementary
              ballet and modern dance classes offered during the academic year. Includes
              correspondence and materials regarding classes and workshops held as a part of the
              Community Outreach Program, established in 1969 under Walter Nicks to involve the
              community in dance. Dance and movement classes were offered to mothers and young
              children, teenagers, and the elderly. Also includes material regarding Friends of ADF,
              an organization formed in 1976 to generate income for the festival and to bring the
              festival and community closer together. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically and alphabetically by subject.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_082d88ac4d2ba2b61ab5c8979b517622" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Development and Fundraising, 1948-1981</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_50f3a364f89c0416c27fa3c93f199363" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1f1173eb489bf513884fd4a90393dc95">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains materials relating to ADF's search for and development of possible funding
              sources.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_81899e58c67e5193e904a186f030bfe1" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Individual Donors, 1948-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">42
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_8c0c0f3539357e12bcb28d4bcdbb8876" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">4</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_506b7f91e27528d85be280cd0380d2e0">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, drafts, form letters, administrative materials,
                sponsors/patrons lists, receipts, lists of complementary tickets, ticket order
                forms, and donor solicitation letters and forms. Contains correspondence to and from
                individuals making donations and lists of donors receiving complementary tickets. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically and then alphabetically by subject or donor name.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_83c49b5d09a2337d6e6ede695c551bee" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Foundations and Funding Organizations, 1948-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.25 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_2ac5c43c22e1d39bd5076c3e66b32dcb" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">4</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_28ce89409f4eec59c9f169882baebce1">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, publicity materials, administration materials, schedules,
                grant information, summary reports, and newspaper clippings. Groups contacted with
                funding requests included educational institutions, state and federal government
                organizations, and private corporations. Of interest are materials regarding various
                Ford Foundation grants including the 1972-1973 grant funding the ADF Repertory
                Company and the 1971-1976 National Endowment of the Arts funding for the Dance
                Critics Conference. Materials overlap with Community Development series, and in kind
                donations from local organizations are filed there. </p>
              <p> Arranged alphabetically by organization name and then chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_f204921c24064666a44e50468f1413f8" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>A-N</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_58519affb736cedb3fa5f5b4115be6df" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">4</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_2d44e951fc919ebbda90173f111929f8" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>N-W</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_e7759196d08fc71ebd18cb538f28ea1e" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">5</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_e928787d3e74e8854a2e5dcb10a72411" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Development Office, 1948-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_fb895bdc8d418df1500d846edd32e8f0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">6</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_531b95de9418ad24803ef30b45de10f8">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, administrative materials, potential donors, form letters,
                budgets, publicity materials, schedules, and lists of grants received. Materials
                include correspondence regarding funding suggestions and publicity materials for a
                1974 panel on government funding and the drive to find matching funds to keep ADF at
                Connecticut College during the summer of 1977. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_9af97a3825afb512c7d51ac0886eaa6d" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Directors' Files, circa 1924-1977</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_df79f855a1e82d26600651699095b83f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">6</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_a0260ca1dd79db4993e8b1e9357ac44d" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Martha Hill, circa 1940-1969</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c22dbc6c6708f77a529fee2fa4a543ae" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">6</container>
            </did>
            <bioghist id="aspace_a1ecff43e1c603da523e9f7fc3291645">
              <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
              <p>Martha Hill, dance teacher and administrator, was a director of the Bennington
                summer school. From 1931 until 1951, she was a member of the dance faculty at
                Bennington and of the Department of Physical Education of the School of Education of
                New York University. In 1951 she became head of the new dance department of the
                Juilliard School in New York. In 1953, she became "advisory" co-director of the
                festival, leaving Ruth Bloomer as director. Though she no longer headed the
                administration, Hill remained an active member of the board of directors for the
                dance school and the festival.</p>
            </bioghist>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e9e9d618d267f5dac1cd58e4c32c095e">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains teaching materials, schedules, correspondence, budget information,
                recommendations for the ADF, in-house materials, a transcript, a telegram,
                advertising materials, and form letters. Of interest are the 1947 planning materials
                for the 1948 School of the Dance. These materials include information on locations,
                budget, and classes. Also, a 1966 form letter urging "Colleagues in Dance" to write
                to their congressmen to encourage congressional support of dance as a performing art
                and materials on the 1969 presentation of an honorary doctorate to Martha Hill
                Davies by the trustees and faculty of Bennington College.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_46b52d74f3dc416ce73c5f67266a76fb" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>American Dance Festival and School of Dance Planning,
                  1947-1957</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_dbdeb7ec95c288112443707bcfe65938" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_24bb98713d899702f8b39991094bf183" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Personal, 1948-1963</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_8edf151ec6f498ab5bcda4599a6b1ebb" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_81e3b70dab9c691533dc951e1c25dcc0" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Placement and Recommendations, 1948-1952</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_06908cc79ee7bb2ba04b28f1ae8b630d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">7</container>
              </did>
              <userestrict id="aspace_a1feb93bf6603518cc8826c61bc71698">
                <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                <p>RESTRICTED</p>
              </userestrict>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_b60346aee5d08898155729ad64d71910" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Professional Activities, 1948-1969</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_913e3cb253237b8b0532cc1c9f94d6b4" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_c8c3624859ef24a6fa034d7bbc74fb65" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Teaching Materials, circa 1942</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_453e4912f03692635fe109cdbf3c2e75" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_fab4e677549fddab229a40357744078a" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Ruth Bloomer, circa 1924-1959</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_8fadfaefc57158d10ef39c326103e6d3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">6</container>
            </did>
            <bioghist id="aspace_e3363a30af14269eb990c5677f669fba">
              <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
              <p>Ruth Bloomer had been a student at the first Bennington session and subsequently
                received her B.S. and M.A. degrees from New York University. She taught at the
                University of Oregon, the University of Michigan, and Denison University, and in
                1945, she came to Connecticut College as the modern dance teacher. In 1953, with
                Martha Hill assuming "advisory" status, Bloomer assumed responsibility for the
                administration of the summer program. She resigned her position in 1958, but stated
                that she would remain a member of the advisory board.</p>
            </bioghist>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_39ecc899abe1fd83dc4c2b6b86765141">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains personal writings, technique card examples, personal notes, costume
                designs, course materials, programs, correspondence, form letters, advertisements,
                newspaper clippings, telegrams, recommendations, resumes, jobs listings,
                administrative materials, publicity materials, and information on a 1957 conference
                for festival managers. Much of the correspondence to and from Bloomer regards job
                placements and recommendations. Her writings include pieces on a variety of subjects
                pertaining to dance including oriental dance, men and dancing, application of
                methods, the function of criticism and critics, and teacher training.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_c026fee752722218b21610847c7b5647" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>American Dance Festival, 1949-1959</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_309fd688d8a5ecf3be5b5f7c49982273" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_5ad8140af1e184888c6bb2d3057deebf" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Personal, 1952-1958</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_1ce01cef6aedae1a84a64ce7f94d2bcd" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_b110b558d04d00c8c5ee4d2a25239f76" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Placement and Recommendations, 1948-1959</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_cc410240723a01e7cc61305886153994" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">7</container>
              </did>
              <userestrict id="aspace_4d39a72457e4019c3a070f6035e8c073">
                <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                <p>RESTRICTED</p>
              </userestrict>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_c7f56b9228ba05909f3f7c615d71f3ac" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Professional Activities, Writings, and Printed Materials circa
                  1924-1958</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_2d8e9596bcdf86676de32ecfdab93b5d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_fd84af4fb3fab4b68c649ac12c028019" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Teaching Materials, 1933-1944</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_d39294fdc4aa7b071d6cb8724f4ff77a" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_83f88f97df6bf5fff34707d0c5df0fa5" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Jeanette Schlottmann, circa 1959-1963</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c950c80e7a807b226d56350d2c604d97" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">6</container>
            </did>
            <bioghist id="aspace_b8ffa3b109e51f5084d7f8a1f0384117">
              <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
              <p>Jeanette Schlottmann had been a member of Anne Schley Duggan's modern dance group
                in Denton, TX. She received her M.A. in Denton at the Texas Woman's University and
                later joined its dance faculty. She taught there until 1950, when she moved to New
                York, studied with Jose Limon, Martha Graham, and Louis Horst, and found a position
                at Barnard College. In 1959, Schlottmann was appointed director of the Connecticut
                College School of the Dance and the American Dance Festival. One of her first
                decisions was to remove the "the" from the title and change the name to the
                Connecticut College School of Dance. In 1962, she established the summer touring
                company, Dance Advance, under the directorship of Janet Mansfield Soares. After the
                1962 season, citing her marriage as a reason, Schlottmann resigned from Connecticut
                College and returned to Barnard College.</p>
            </bioghist>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_6ce0ee7e142794bf5b59b1df0a5ee2f4">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, job openings and application materials, resumes, form
                letters, programs, brochures and advertising materials, schedule for the 1959 Dance
                Teachers Guild Annual Convention, newspaper clippings, surveys, invitations, and
                telegrams.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_9196649e808b6193a225fddb915c6c96" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>American Dance Festival, 1959-1963</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_53e8e923a56fc27dcd38dc167950c726" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_564b2f6b23bbf356a4571e5a78d43929" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Personal, 1959-1963</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_be315d7b5cf28cfb9440355bbda5eb7d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_fdae379657f7d51ad07ae55d9c6c544f" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Placement and Recommendations, 1959-1963</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_bd9f36a448d3394c0e8e038fb3fb451f" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">7</container>
              </did>
              <userestrict id="aspace_65dbf98fddd2044ffcf01939d9d55020">
                <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                <p>RESTRICTED</p>
              </userestrict>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_e36e4d368b42f5da78074a0a1a7133ac" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Professional Activities, 1959-1961</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_f009e96f7d9d8b76d0d8df403dd66fb4" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_bf9a58f8fab622bdf3e0b104ad871f5f" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Theodora Wiesner, circa 1963-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_4cca8abbfa3986a11faa08a9d620e2eb" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">6</container>
            </did>
            <bioghist id="aspace_fc4c8786690e964a441274f654d27618">
              <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
              <p>In 1930, Theodora Wiesner received her undergraduate degree from the University of
                Wisconsin in Madison. She moved to New York to do graduate work at New York
                University and then divided her time between her studies and teaching at various
                universities. She attended all but two of the Bennington summer sessions. After
                serving as a lieutenant commander in the U.S. Navy women's reserve during World War
                II, she returned to her studies on her doctorate, which she received in 1952. In
                1949 she worked as an administrative assistant at the Connecticut College School of
                Dance. In 1950 she became director of the Dance program at Brooklyn College. With
                the 1962 retirement of Jeanette Schlottmann, the administrative board elected
                Wiesner director. In 1969, Wiesner recommended that a new director be appointed. In
                1975, she retired from her directorship at Brooklyn College.</p>
            </bioghist>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_788290ef697cb4c94bf2f244f0d686c3">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, job openings and application materials, resumes, form
                letters, invitations, newspaper clippings, brochures and advertising materials,
                schedules, surveys, and telegrams. Of interest is a 1963 letter from Charles
                Reinhart regarding his previous summer as executive director and 1964-1965
                correspondence regarding the possibility of Balasaraswati appearing at the 1965
                festival. Also present is a listing of Theodora Wiesner's duties as director of the
                festival and a letter from Wiesner to Oakes Ames, President of Connecticut College
                regarding her analysis of the question of ADF property ownership.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_545c590ee07711426e816cc96943e6d4" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>American Dance Festival, 1963-1977</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">8
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_5bc59f8f18319efd7644d0dc22ff9bf5" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_b32fd67125a6d776567d37fbd1cfc0e7" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Personal, 1964-1967</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_26838220c9edab261b652ff30267261d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_bb65dcaec6c8c211e43ab2530e6c8803" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Placement and Recommendations, 1963-1969</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_00e404343e8a6f2910b2b14c3c24497e" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">7</container>
              </did>
              <userestrict id="aspace_fe01b018993d5c93c86edeb84c500b2f">
                <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                <p>RESTRICTED</p>
              </userestrict>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_a4482acb8317f3df5680a65899114faa" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Professional Activities, 1964-1967</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_d7482534e754bea62deb709d24db10e7" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_efdaef68b90b8bddb4fc1d9ee199f2a8" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Charles Reinhart, circa 1968-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_d4031f3313650eca3c61b09427974ac1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">6</container>
            </did>
            <bioghist id="aspace_3abc8162c04c0983c2790d48b828f3ba">
              <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
              <p>After having spent several years in publicity, including at Jacob's Pillow in the
                summers of 1960 and 1961, Charles Reinhart opened a management office in 1962. Paul
                Taylor was one of his first major clients. In 1966, he helped establish the NEA's
                Dance Touring Program. He then ran the DTP for ten years. In 1968, Theodora Wiesner
                decided to resign control of the festival and recommended that a new director be
                appointed. The festival board and Connecticut College's administrative staff
                appointed Charles Reinhart. Reinhart also served as director of Jacob's Pillow in
                1974.</p>
            </bioghist>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_72059e070a2945e31c9a7577b11a2d46">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, materials pertaining to a 1969 Performing Arts Aid
                Meeting, memos, form letters, information on the Harkness Memorial State Park
                submitted to the Connecticut Commission on the Arts, newspaper clippings, and
                resumes.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_4bcbfecabd5ad1a93f2eea5f112c4335" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>American Dance Festival, 1968-1977</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_303c869c99d816bbb4c8c2f8f1088f24" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_8b6a5ab5b674cc519beb876769bf52d8" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Personal, 1968-1977</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_4b84c033cc42556a62b3bd0519bd1c37" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_56d3f4b7d2ffb528741e645c20da215f" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Placement and Recommendations, 1969-1977</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_bea19ee425c21f40c0d8f32df19f6c1d" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">7</container>
              </did>
              <userestrict id="aspace_84d6af11f77803d1c7efd04fdde6a8b1">
                <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                <p>RESTRICTED</p>
              </userestrict>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_2f89a9aa25bf0d4e60bd8997d2fd103b" level="subseries">
              <did>
                <unittitle>Professional Activities, 1968-1977</unittitle>
                <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                    folders</extent></physdesc>
                <container id="aspace_e93a3a557dcae56c6d31ca38f7692b04" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">6</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_cfcbb76510798ecc4a8886a53e4527fd" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Connecticut College, circa 1940-1981</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.83 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_8cf1df35f3bc24529d34e134d848ec73" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_85de934d0958b2f710f28711a2009ea3">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_ea233b52e44c1af51cfc2bbc74465e38">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, memos, form letters, articles of incorporation, legal
              documents, schedules, administrative materials, budgets, drafts, newspaper clippings,
              brochures, publicity materials, programs, application forms, floor plans, lists of
              faculty, staff, and students, policy information, library information including lists
              of overdue library books, campus maps and information, course lists, security reports,
              Connecticut visitor information, and a 1972 proposal to establish a MFA in dance at
              Connecticut College. The documents portray ADF's working relationship with Connecticut
              College and New York University as host institutions. Materials refer to decades of
              policy decisions, organization, and administration actions.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4493dc7dcf55e5982bec31a347adb29c" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Facilities and Central Services, 1947-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.42 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_477a4de190768bac67f981ff1fb41550" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_b5b88adb73c4c63e8c9296d18b145219">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, memos, form letters, floor plans, facilities measurements,
              facilities information, material requests, request forms, room assignments, contracts
              and rental agreements, schedules, sign-up sheets, administrative materials, and
              brochures and publicity materials. Documents refer to the use and maintenance of the
              facilities and materials utilized by the American Dance Festival at Connecticut
              College. Facilities include performance and rehearsal space, dormitories, and common
              areas such as the swimming pool and library. Correspondence between Facility Services
              and ADF refers to festival organization and closing coordination and supplies needed.
              Other correspondence refers to rehearsal space, scheduling, fire drills, materials
              needed, and police scheduling.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e2d3a05ad0981313cf0f39c54ee338a1" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Finance, 1947-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7.5 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_d0dfb4568f399591ad733f430891359d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">9</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_b50cba03c75b69d23df50932b26bfeaa">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains finance records of the organization except for records of Development and
              Fundraising individual donors and funding organizations. Documents reflect the
              functions of the Finance Office. </p>
            <p> Arranged first chronologically, then alphabetically within each year by the
              following subjects:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
              <item>Accounts</item>
              <item>Budgets</item>
              <item>Correspondence</item>
              <item>General Ledger</item>
              <item>Payroll</item>
            </list>
            <p>Accounts are further divided into the following subjects:</p>
            <list type="ordered">
              <item>Community Projects</item>
              <item>Companies</item>
              <item>Donations and Grant Income</item>
              <item>Facilities</item>
              <item>Festival</item>
              <item>General and Administrative</item>
              <item>Insurance</item>
              <item>School</item>
              <item>Special Projects</item>
              <item>Students</item>
            </list>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_3d1721d68009d63a44cb13dfc52dc240" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1947-1959</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_23564eed8a3e94abaf6a514302a1feaa" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">9</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c20f4ee1f6ae45435ca402671b8ec7e5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1960-1965</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_eb7553f50c29cc00dfa21990eb52b3c1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">10</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0a02796fdff5df5f4b750f2d429c2960" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1966-1971</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_7da493b171ed6cd23706d26f97bb76ed" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">11</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_34398d5af6c218fd96f025ccd1c87f2e" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1972-1974</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_090ebf6b92d4f4ffde62daee5c6e877a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">12</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_99fe8d08ef117c0230000722226bad8f" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1974-1976</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_723bf31b4d6bc9fa991d4e542a84a390" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">13</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_93343bce9d7138f4e15a2bef7b42ac79" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1976-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_f6367b9192a2b770ea202cceae15d590" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">14</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_30520db30eb0d2921c0a22fdfe3d700d" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Legal Documents, 1975-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_9cda7e9becb233fcc206ef9b8a3453d0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">15</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_21f08c0ea0dc6d717a2969ad220b43d1">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains IRS documents, correspondence, tax exemption information, press releases,
              articles of incorporations, bylaws, and nondiscrimination policy information.
              Materials refer to legal issues pertaining to the incorporation of ADF. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_061802e957cffe4964986e93860dd491" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Personnel, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.05 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_fbb64baf4fc6077d334873981c2e48f0" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">16</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_4dba9fcec8dee3ec2df151a60e384091">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, resumes, administrative materials, form letters, newspaper
              clippings, grant applications, job advertisements, and faculty and staff listings
              related to employment of ADF administrative staff. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <userestrict id="aspace_9935a68319067070fcdcd070a0d4fafa">
            <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
            <p>RESTRICTED</p>
          </userestrict>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4b4f92baf3e623180922429b5ebf07a6" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Press Office, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_f25f28576ac0fd4b11a400e9ca4be113" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">15</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_055d4d051dab49c16e140fe304874628">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, press releases, drafts, form letters, invitation lists,
              mailing lists, schedules, budgets, telegrams, summary reports, advertising forms,
              publicity materials, radio interview information, advertisement materials, attendance
              lists, proofs, critics and press lists, critics' complementary tickets materials,
              newspaper clippings, reviews, advertisement distribution lists, and press conference
              materials. Materials relate publicity and press coverage for all aspects of ADF
              including school classes, festival performances, and community outreach programs.
              Materials also include coverage in publicity sources ranging from ADF press releases
              to newspaper reviews and radio interviews. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_da86efbdf054bdaf2c1f7ab1a4c89e4b" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1948-1970</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_37ddd7f3fd650554d260080ff1d4c6b8" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">15</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5f31afaa1bcd5a93a0111b83e0af1177" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1971-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_b8c6e4a17c1c557fa2a782aedf837e6d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">17</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_776e47ce8ea6c45ca3379bbc62ee9bf6" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Publications Office, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_17d0fdfa0630cedc75485559179e6296" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">17</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_36de1f41eff4dd8b484e5de6d1950d90">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, bulletins, publicity materials, drafts, proofs, costs
              sheets, program advertisement order forms, form letters, schedules, mailing lists,
              newspaper clippings, purchase orders, and receipts. Much of the materials refers to
              the annual school course guide, information booklets, ticket information, and the
              individual program playbills. These materials include schedules, course listings,
              artist information, lists of advertisers, and advertisement proofs. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_5d6dd57066b51965204d687091d9c6fd" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1948-1963</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_fce185bcef12034345aca6fa9ef9ba90" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">17</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_2b07cecba49571079994bea4af9bbd3a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1964-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_e2c87df0e0667c5c1dd3040e4fe1632e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">18</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_0cf0544e19363a51bfda9016a4b2a16b" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Social Gatherings and Parties, 1950-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">17
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_f1c640235dd32864ef827f18af44aef6" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">19</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f3a40d4bcda3ff626215f5b95f888784">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains guest lists, faculty and student listings, correspondence, invitations, form
              letters, schedules, hostess lists, and food and supplies lists. Materials refer to the
              variety of brunches, dinners, receptions, and social gatherings that occurred during
              the American Dance Festival, including materials referring to the 25th Anniversary
              Opening Gala and Reception and the 1977 reception to honor Sir Peter Ramsbotham, Lady
              Ramsbotham, and the London Contemporary Dance theater Company. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_aa7ed935bc6627042e9e784ad0267b89" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>New Site Search, 1976-1977</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_c346ece03e29c4b53d87df5489546487" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">19</container>
          </did>
          <bioghist id="aspace_2737e4c8d553296b1ec92bb8025234d2">
            <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
            <p>In 1976, Connecticut College president Oakes Ames claimed that hosting ADF cost the
              college too much money and opted to charge the festival an additional yearly fee to
              cover operating costs. Festival Director Charles Reinhart, working with Administrative
              Directors Lisa Booth and Mary Jane Ingram, began considering a move to a different
              location. In August 1976, the Connecticut Commission on the Arts set up an inquiry
              into the future of ADF in Connecticut. The panel made two recommendations: that ADF
              should remain at Connecticut College for the 1977 season, and that both parties should
              undertake a joint study into the relationship between the festival and the
              college.</p>
            <p> ADF decided to terminate its relationship with Connecticut College and issued a
              press release in November 1976 stating their intention to move, resulting in phone
              calls and written requests from prospective sites. ADF compiled an initial list of
              possible locations. Meanwhile, the Connecticut Commission on the Arts study continued,
              with those involved knowing that ADF was leaving. In addition to financial disputes,
              the study highlighted other problems, mainly a perceived change in Connecticut
              College's attitude towards the festival: study participants felt that the college
              viewed ADF as a business proposition rather than an artistic entity. Also mentioned
              was a shortage of adequate facilities at Connecticut College.</p>
            <p> Throughout the study, ADF had been moving forward with plans to research potential
              locations. By August 1977 Reinhart, Booth, and Ingram had narrowed their choices and
              asked for proposals from 14 institutions. An advisory panel to help choose the new
              site was created. Unable to make a final selection, the panel decided to request more
              information from three front-runners: the University of Wisconsin at Milwaukee, the
              University of Massachusetts at Amherst, and Duke University. After receiving the
              additional information, the panel reconvened to discuss their findings and ultimately
              chose Duke University.</p>
          </bioghist>
          <c03 id="aspace_228b0de5fbe70b409ac9541c1172ab0d" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Decision Process, circa 1976-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_321c5b279754f5f524cb3aa0619381f7" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">19</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_f50311186b7d46f8c3d2b893165cc66d">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, press releases, meeting drafts, and notes explaining the
                events leading up to and the motivation behind the move, encompassing a time frame
                beginning in August 1976 with a Connecticut Commission on the Arts inquiry into a
                financial dispute between ADF and Connecticut College, and ending with work
                generated by an Advisory Panel assembled to choose the ADF's new location. Also
                included is a study of ADF's purpose and its relationship to Connecticut College and
                initial work regarding selecting a new site. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_fe0c71576caa1abf79ef4652b29d73d1" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Potential Sites, circa 1976-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">11
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_a2ab94f05aa92df50aab34d1195c0634" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">19</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_f7ee842a29d9de26491f1371901e6b82">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains information and correspondence from over 40 universities, colleges, and
                arts organizations interested in hosting ADF. The 11 proposals from the most
                seriously considered sites are included, as well as additional requested information
                from the three final candidates. </p>
              <p> Arranged alphabetically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_af57f80b9b38980a33344632ba474270" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Performance, 1948-1977 and undated</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_148546d30b7e1c3e4540488d88c18a65" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >19</container>
        </did>
        <bioghist id="aspace_333dd4ce54912376cdaf332d7bb460dc">
          <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
          <p>From 1948 to 1968, festival performances were held during the last part of the dance
            school's six-week course and were open to the public as well as the dance school
            community. For several years, the performances were held during the last week or
            extended weekend of the school. Gradually, performances began to be held during the last
            two or three weeks. Beginning in 1972, performances were given throughout the summer. In
            1976 and 1977, ADF also held a public performance season in Newport, Rhode Island, in
            addition to the regular season in New London, Connecticut.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <c02 id="aspace_7b17906a34aca81506e971d80cb6128b" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Commissions, 1954-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_2878fa44c852bf93acdd0dea80f36fa8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">19</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_d767676ed74fd70bcd1fdc9b3ce0d113">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Arranged chronologically and within each year alphabetically by company or artist
              name.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <bioghist id="aspace_804a2af0a616ae56c3c4626deb989092">
            <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
            <p>1954 marked the first year that the School of the Dance commissioned choreography.
              The recipient was long-time ADF faculty member and noted choreographer, Jose Limon,
              and he created "The Traitor" for the summer season. Funds for Limon's work came from a
              surplus in the previous season's budget, but in subsequent years, ADF sought
              foundations and individuals to sponsor commissions. During the Connecticut period,
              commissioned artists included Jose Limon, Doris Humphrey, Erick Hawkins, Vivian Fine,
              Paul Draper, Lucas Hoving, Paul Taylor, Ruth Currier, and Rudy Perez.</p>
          </bioghist>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_96a1b417569788ff75ac56cd5423b12b">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains proposals and correspondence commissioning artists, both dancers and
              musicians, to create works for performance during the ADF summer season.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_7e5b48dde099532c8adf8eddc7ce2980" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Company Travel and Accommodations, 1952-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.3 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_dd05bd815cad8dfc3ffb3472143aff69" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">19</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_e34daa135928779ffb5b194ec823e655">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, administrative lists, dormitory floor plans, and itineraries
              concerning performing companies', orchestras', and musical accompanists' travel
              arrangements, housing, and meals.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_22842e21a2a54fbc1c1248249532eca3" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Performance Contracts, 1957-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.3 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_3c878a1035fc8c8777b32cce95900697" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">19</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_175be49736bbf32ccbb0f0daed11b320">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains contracts and letters of agreement between ADF and performing companies and
              musicians and musical groups, including companies that were brought to ADF as a part
              of special projects, such as Music and Dance.</p>
            <p> Arranged in chronologically and divided into special project categories when
              applicable. Within each year and special project category, materials are arranged
              alphabetically by company or artist name.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_33f0ae0cdfabee231bfa23099cabe672" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Performers' Files, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_35b6225809a99535943ea0a6ea3ebb13" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">20</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_00ec3ded089c5542090c03ecfb70ae5a">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains letters to and from performers, schedules, company rosters, blank copies of
              contracts, and limited biographical materials relating to the company, solo and duet
              performers, or guest artists. Records often discuss plans for choreography, as well as
              logistics about scheduling, housing, production, performance, and publicity.
              Performers' Files include performers and musicians involved in special projects that
              were active during the 1970s, such as Music and Dance, Emerging Generation, and the
              Dance Touring Project.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically and within each year alphabetically by surname within
              company name.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4d3757e5b5f09fadd5453bf8007f4f0a" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Performance Office, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_9ba16b48169d514703a75b16b87f6e10" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">21</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_0d68c2f10d9b0b64de30a08b6d6f9299">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains records that document the administrative side of coordinating performances,
              but not the decision-making processes of season programming (see Season Programming
              series), including information about mailings regarding the performance season,
              requests for performance season schedules (letters of interest), correspondence
              regarding contracting musicians and/or musical groups to accompany festival
              performances, correspondence with ADF-hired orchestra managers, such as Arnold
              Goldberg, and internal correspondence about the administration of the performance
              season. No official "Performance Office" existed during ADF's years at Connecticut
              College.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_661d0dcfb7f9b240913aba93cfea5485" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Production, 1948-1977 and undated</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_9c9dce0489932aa8254a3977f1706729" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">21</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_433c7c853b2821ad1ec8b8f386ad4574">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, schedules, lighting cues and plots, costume and set design
              notes and sketches, lists of orchestra personnel, and production notes. Occasionally
              includes materials regarding other events that took place in the theater which
              required technical assistance. Crew Correspondence documents the participation of
              individual crew members, such as the Technical Director, Stage Manager, and Lighting
              Designer. Other correspondence in this series covers requests for theater equipment
              from theater supply companies or dance companies, including correspondence in early
              years with Jean Rosenthal at Theater Production Service. Also includes correspondence
              and notes from artists, such as Doris Humphrey, Pauline Lawrence Limon (for Jose
              Limon), and Paul Taylor, about costume and set design or specific production needs for
              choreographic works. Costume files may include correspondence from the choreographer,
              measurements for specific dancers, and lists of materials used to construct costumes
              for various choreographic pieces. Set designs may also include correspondence from the
              choreographer, notes, and diagrams for set designs. Although light plots and cues do
              not exist for every year or for every piece performed, a fair number of diagrams are
              available in this series, and are labeled by choreographer or performing group if
              known.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically with subdivisions by subject: Crew Correspondence,
              Rehearsal Schedules, Costume Designs, and Music Permissions.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_bb566e64b00246901d90717a36a83c7a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1948-1970</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_9e940acc8fdb78e20a52f5c9e1d8953a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">21</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_6e159fc85d6763ebf447eb1dc0dc7af7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1970-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_63ec112f18145d1fc4b0d2d342080642" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">22</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_a6f1a17bce06b94b700e9d3625d84967" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Program Materials, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.75 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_434997b51bed76daa9107e164a2ca3f4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">22</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_764f44dac94196bdc7c70d817680ef09">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains lists of repertory to be performed in a given ADF season, correspondence
              from performers listing choreography to be performed, program notes, and rough drafts
              and proofs of programs. Includes program materials of most performances, formal and
              informal, that were used to create printed programs that accompanied performances.
              Final versions of programs are files in Printed Material in the Programs series.
              Playbills are filed in Playbills in the Printed Material series.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_ed8d74e583d67328803d54984a0c579f" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Season Programming, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.75 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_f22ca9161f3b2276290e8b29da1d9550" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">22</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_f5c359b484cfcac9ddbef3cca6b8013f">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains letters of interest to and from potential performers, lists of the season's
              performers, correspondence, and administrative materials concerning planning the
              season as a whole. Also includes materials created by the Festival Committee
              (initially known as the Executive Council), a group that determined the season
              programming from 1948 to 1968. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically with categories, where materials exist: Letters of
              Interest, Festival Committee, and Performers unable to attend.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_ca8f025c58d8e52e13851eef89dd8e54" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1948-1960</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_eec8a45edd2f3723d08cd0c7da9374fd" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">22</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_ea7bbb99c4973476aba0151dabdf02d0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1961-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_3513851a011104d96681ec2ec9067140" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">23</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_9f69f8898a8791e87893dc6f6b78d1e9" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Special Projects, 1947-1985</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_180ba2bc65fd819da12d2945d202ad74" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >23</container>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_1ddd5d2621a5c6363f24ea9a62bfeafe" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>ADF Repertory Company, 1972-1973</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_b65d5e2daa7fa24c2646009dd5f623d8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">23</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_76f0965f24cc954fc5422276f1166479">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains materials that document the history of the 1972 American Dance Festival
              Repertory Company from its organization through its performance reviews.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <bioghist id="aspace_eb3378c3c906200e3cadcdce0f0adfaa">
            <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
            <p>The American Dance Festival Repertory Company was formed in 1972, recreating several
              important, older works. From its conception, the company was organized with the intent
              to exist for only one season. ADF also produced a film with Ted Steeg Productions
              documenting the choreography performed. The ADF Repertory Company Advisory Committee
              members included Charles Reinhart, Martha Hill, Teddy Wiesner, Jeannette Roosevelt,
              and Walter Terry. Each member submitted a list of potential works to recreate and then
              together, the committee narrowed the list to five works: Martha Graham's <title
                xlink:type="simple" render="italic">El Penitente</title>, Doris Humphrey's <title
                xlink:type="simple" render="italic">New Dance</title> and <title xlink:type="simple"
                render="italic">With My Red Fires</title>, Jose Limon's <title xlink:type="simple"
                render="italic">Emperor Jones</title>, and Charles Weidman's <title
                xlink:type="simple" render="italic">Flickers</title>. In addition, Rudy Perez was
              asked to create a new work to commemorate the achievements of the ADF.</p>
          </bioghist>
          <c03 id="aspace_93d3eacd4c1b71d34b7f2f649839a1d1" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Administration, 1972</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_0fa9d384db30aa6854b9917d1a94770a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_d58bfaf60d92c2a713add6ea8d803a49">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains Advisory committee materials, correspondence with dancers and
                choreographers, administrative materials, forms and form letters, and reviews and
                background materials on certain pieces. </p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_296b2fafc03cf3f853456b0406bc5a55" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Films, 1972-1973</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_c266d35826d3fa85ebc99a20adb5ed0d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">23</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_0fce634b3ea16386ff9cddc99a02d5f6">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains a proposal for film, administrative materials, contracts, and
                correspondence.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_089bb741a8ac74e37cc0a220a2b4b47c" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Artists in the Schools, 1971-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_84146956694d07ab9eef617d4aa5e3d4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">23</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_31435a39987a943977b04a1d57b8d424">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains organization materials, transcription, form letters, correspondence,
              workshop materials, and information packets pertaining to the Artists in the Schools
              program.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <bioghist id="aspace_eb6e36c59f71586de517d47d62adc924">
            <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
            <p>ADF hosted the annual workshop for this program beginning in the summer of 1972.
              Charles Reinhart was National Coordinator of the program from 1972-1977.</p>
          </bioghist>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_98473fe170420cdfcb6236694ab5782d" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Dance Advance, 1962-1968</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_5b44d616ea0bb9c21db3c2e8e9d41f31" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">23</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1e8a2eacd237d965d3c40c027aeddb6b">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Consists of correspondence relating to performance, schedules of performance, and
              printed programs listing pieces, choreographers, and performers, at Dance Advance
              events.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <bioghist id="aspace_a531fe134cacc02b6dee6f05aa40dde6">
            <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
            <p>Dance Advance was a touring group of advanced students attending the summer session
              of the Connecticut College School of Dance. The group was instituted to acquaint a
              greater audience with modern dance and to provide students with performance and
              choreography opportunities. The students were expected to audition previously created
              pieces and to provide their own costumes and music. Dance Advance performed several
              dates each summer at many sites in New England, including colleges, camps, and local
              festivals. The group was also filmed by several New England television stations.</p>
          </bioghist>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_3e31a036f7385dd2ca6ac3f90f7d565a" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Dance Critics Conference, 1970-1985</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_a4dfe9bf20ee2f4b484e8fedd1bf02b4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">23</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_730be884cc874496ea10138357e28b89">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains a list of participants, organizational materials, correspondence, form
              letters, application forms, conference reviews from participants, and film request
              materials. While a participants list contains the names of attendees from 1970-1985,
              other materials in this series end in 1977.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <bioghist id="aspace_d82f8bbc848c300289ee117afbda1073">
            <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
            <p>The Dance Critics Conference grew out of a 1967 summer course in critical writing
              taught by Selma Jeanne Cohen. The Conference was a three week (initially four week)
              seminar that brought together a small group of practicing journalists from the United
              States and Canada to gain greater understanding of how to review and write about
              dance. Dance criticism techniques were expanded through methods such as a daily
              movement class, ADF program attendance, ADF class visitation, dance film observation,
              and active critique sessions with respected dance critics. In these sessions,
              participants discussed topics such as writing style and problems relating to dance and
              dance review in the critics' home communities, completed writing assignments including
              reviews, and discussed one another's reviews.</p>
          </bioghist>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_29b03faec5535ad6d46eab9f63f6ba3c" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Dance Touring Program, 1976</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_a7e7bcbac1833aa080e183e456773098" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">23</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_23596adce4e37670b12e9536c46470a6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Consists of a schedule for the 1976-1977 Artists-In-Schools Dance Component Summer
              Workshop comprised of the Dance Touring Program Coordinator's Workshop and the June
              25-July 1, 1976 American Dance Festival at the New London campus of Connecticut
              College. More information about the ADF's involvement in the Dance Touring Program, a
              National Endowment for the Arts-sponsored program, can be found in the Administration
              series, under the Foundations and Funding Organizations sub series.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_92d32c1e91e872c743d53be3610aae8d" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Dance/Television Workshop, 1973-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_4b3a9406461f5bbf1b88c3eb5f1d8244" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">25</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_e34dd9d8b2de6c90509d537d599d48a4">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, letters of interest, applications, publicity, administrative
              materials, and participant evaluations pertaining to workshops held at ADF for
              television professionals.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_25d88da4b6c3d1f20f8540c5b794b964" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Applications, 1973-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_58409020ab41996b27afd116c5a17c95" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">24</container>
            </did>
            <userestrict id="aspace_722ea66ff1d527d5bfa07433f38bb44a">
              <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
              <p>RESTRICTED</p>
            </userestrict>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d120333fc315739a61edf2599f92860a" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Emerging Generation, 1974</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_2d34a37c55e84f85828f9f803d2f2e6d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">25</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_06acb557bb12a5f4c3159733a52b16c8">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, personal notation, form letters, and a press release
              regarding the 1974 Emerging Generation program designed to highlight up-and-coming
              choreographers and their companies, including Trisha Brown and Group, Laura Dean and
              Dance Company, Nora Guthrie and Ted Rotante, the Multigravitational Experiment Group,
              Sara and Jerry Pearson, and Pilobolus Dance Theatre.</p>
            <p> Arranged alphabetically by subject.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_adbb1520f92cf345987eff2fd7c4ba6a" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Exhibits, 1949-1973</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_a08e48a9b672fa02923eb9e81e449575" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">25</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_638199675f21bf24628b1928e81d258c">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, form letters, administrative materials, and reviews
              regarding exhibits held at, or circulated by, the American Dance Festival, including
              traveling exhibits in the 1960s of slides and photographs designed to cultivate
              interest in the School of Dance.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_06b604be5acd4ab4d1c44103cdbf1859" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Film and Notation Project, 1954-1972</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_8912c7ab16bc209f14771dec74356938" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">25</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_d9f0e675753c3385d4b0e90002e7c63b">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, administration papers, form letters, Labanotation notes, a
              notated musical score, contract information, newsletters, magazine and newspaper
              clippings, advertisements, and reviews.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <bioghist id="aspace_0f90dfb32536208f74ebf7a8f118c53e">
            <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
            <p>The Film Notation project was an effort to preserve contemporary dances on film and
              in notation. Films were made under the direction of Helen Priest Rogers. Lucy Venable,
              President of the Dance Notation Bureau, directed the notation. Initial films were
              silent, but beginning in 1962, some films were made with sound. After 1965, all of
              films were made with sound. Many works were filmed and notated including those of
              Doris Humphrey, Jose Limon, Pauline Koner, Merce Cunningham, Paul Taylor, Alwin
              Nikolais, Ruth Currier, Helen Tamiris, and Charles Weidman.</p>
          </bioghist>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_69e5277ff617d6b7647b6d33abba6c71" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Film Series, 1957-1974</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_f13ff5bd244dde35604e09ce1137e6cd" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">25</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_e2e18ef8675861e6192cc0016860ca3e">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Consists of correspondence, promotional materials, brochures, film lists, press
              releases, administrative materials, rental requests, and ordering information, much of
              it referring to dance films that were available for rental, purchase, or loan from
              various companies and institutions. Also included are correspondence and film lists
              referring to films viewed either individually or as part of a semi-annual film series
              at the School of Dance under the auspices of Selma Jeanne Cohen.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_2ee32babf0767a845b96f6905e01bd53" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Lecture Demonstrations and Panels, 1948-1974</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">23
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_1e84840b8f2a1bf2ad9eefc0117052db" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">25</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_4c06d774cf6a084a2071c85111afa465">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Series contains schedules, dance step instructions, lecture notes, correspondence,
              form letters, registration sheets, newspaper clippings, and programs relating to a
              variety of lectures and demonstrations, including a 1953 Festival appearance by
              Virginia Tanner and members of the Children's Dance Theatre of Brigham Young
              University, a 1964 demonstration of Labanotation in Creative Dance Teaching by
              students of Nadia Chilkovsky of the Philadelphia Dance Academy, a 1965
              lecture-demonstration on Classical Japanese Dance by Shozo Sato, a 1969 critics
              conference that laid the foundation for the 1970 Dance Critics Conference, and
              lectures for 1970s "Horizons in Dance" courses.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d21148876912a6cc84cdd9405dc355b2" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Little Lecture Series, 1951-1970</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">16
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_ee8e34c5338eb82f2d3bacca0c50374d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">26</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_960af3fe3f45831e203706c0a326efc6">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, form letters, publicity materials, administration materials,
              tickets, reviews, newspaper and magazine clippings, course information, and lecture
              notes referring to a lecture series begun in 1951. Included is correspondence with
              potential lecturers (Aaron Copeland and William Schuman, for example) as well as those
              who did lecture including Walter Terry, Martha Graham, Jose Limon, Doris Humphrey, and
              Agnes de Mille. In 1956, the lecture series served as a portion of the Backgrounds and
              Aesthetics of Dance lecture-discussion course directed by George Beiswanger. In 1959
              the series name was changed to the Little Concert-Lecture Series.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_e872e23efa59ea024d804da751928ac2" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Mini-ADFs, 1976-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">16
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_dfcc35840b6f0bb05c5ad620a4aec4b9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">26</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_081bdbda01fac43950453a2c51dcd1e5">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains correspondence, newspaper clippings, form letters, postcards, tourism
              materials, rental forms, budget sheets, press releases, a 1976 prospectus on the
              benefits of Newport, RI, schedules, real estate agency contact information, and
              permits referring to the ADF's stay in Newport during 1976 and 1977. Also contains
              letters and in house documents related to the search for a new site for the
              festival.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <bioghist id="aspace_3ac60604141f6916897973be3ec2a2c9">
            <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
            <p>In 1976, Mayor Humphrey J. Donnelly of Rhode Island invited the festival to Newport.
              After holding its 1976 season of classes and performances in New London, ADF also gave
              a week of performances in Newport. In addition, the festival also held community
              classes and workshops.</p>
          </bioghist>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_80378bd47288f83bf5e3996dec886073" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Music and Dance (MAD), 1974-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_e4f6f83ae0e98a28b734d2b171650678" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">26</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_3356252b4601509af2f400ad7e59f28e">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains schedules, newspaper articles, correspondence, contracts, administration
              materials, press releases, and a NEA grant application regarding Project: Music and
              Dance.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <bioghist id="aspace_3beadf83025aadbbbe8658e1e09dee54">
            <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
            <p>In 1974, Project: Music and Dance (MAD), also known as the Composers-Choreographers
              Workshop, paired experienced choreographers with composers to create new works. The
              works created through the collaborations were Bella Lewitzky's <title
                xlink:type="simple" render="italic">Fire</title>, music by Max Lifchitz, Jennifer
              Muller's <title xlink:type="simple" render="italic">Winter Pieces</title>, music by
              Charles O. B. Curtis-Smith, Manuel Alum's <title xlink:type="simple" render="italic"
                >Yemaya</title>, music by Ira Taxin, and Nancy Meehan's <title xlink:type="simple"
                render="italic">Yellow Paint</title>, music by Rocco di Pietra. The music was
              performed by the St. Paul Chamber Orchestra under the direction of Dennis Russel
              Davies. In 1975, MAD teamed Kathryn Posin and composer Laurie Spiegel and Pilobolus
              and composer Robert Dennis. 1976 included Murray Louis's <title xlink:type="simple"
                render="italic">Glances</title> to music by Dave Brubeck.</p>
          </bioghist>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_432bff0678eddd07ef298edab48e0d65" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Other Projects, 1947-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_0c541f2f367233bc438cbe7a5dbd117d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">26</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_a4364e68af7aff1e1967f04d893770b9">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains programs, administrative materials, diagrams, newspaper clippings, artwork,
              correspondence, schedules, form letters, contracts, and a NEA grant application
              referring to a variety of projects with some association with the American Dance
              Festival, Dance Symposiums held by the Connecticut College Dance Group featuring
              classes and critiques by Louis Horst, Walter Terry, Hazel Johnson, June Dunbar, Ella
              Lukk, Pauline Koner, and David Wood (1954 and 1958), children's programs by the
              Merry-Go-Rounders and the Merrymobile (1959), international projects (1959 and 1961),
              a documentary on the American Dance Festival (1972), and the Total Theatre Project
              film <title xlink:type="simple" render="italic">Taylor's Follies</title>
              (1975-1977).</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_7bc5c5cce12ae4c51dd6e0962041561d" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Press and Publicity Materials, 1934-1977</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_ce1979bb139a50f3cbeca491b2f24628" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >26</container>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_dde6f2c9bf1ee87997acc5a88012f1ab" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Press Coverage, 1934-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.25 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_e71edddc90079181b618c13af8344e0a" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">26</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_5d4b7e0a4aa8971ab83a2650742bebcd">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains press clippings referring to the American Dance Festival and its performers
              and participants.</p>
            <p> Individual files devoted to Martha Graham, Hanya Holm, and Louis Horst, are followed
              by files arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_1366a38834100a484017baab85153307" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1934-1968</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_163d5284b5e31419844e050abb1d08af" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">26</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_7759484bd9973a39887c0f4535266727" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1969-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_843462a56061e1f26f858ef76fe67fbd" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">27</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_50c42813379943d2561472caadbafbcd" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Press Book, 1974</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_49b97e369fd0f9532ba10eff245a011a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">OS1</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_46d4ce441e215fdafb048d941a6b71af" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Press Kits, 1974-1975</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_6c0d4694ce370455e5cd0e80c1d06d94" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">28</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_2575d0026d8f19fa22d9a9974e0edf62">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains press kits made and distributed by ADF containing press releases describing
              the various activities at the school and festival including schedules of events,
              companies performing at the festival, festival programs, projects offered by the
              Community Outreach Program, and workshops and mini-conferences including the Critics
              Conference and the Dance Educators' Workshop. Also includes individual companies'
              publicity materials that were distributed as part of the general press kits.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_55a77e853a8142f1eedac865933f1d8c" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Press Releases, 1936, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.58 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_0b302c648cc100fea9d651bad57bb8e4" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">28</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_2fc6bed03bba05d40766605ca0f1fb9e">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains press releases, schedules, correspondence, and lists of students organized
              according to home state for publicity purposes. Releases include information on
              faculty members, classes, artists, programs to be held, and descriptions of programs
              after the performances. Also includes correspondence regarding press releases, ticket
              order forms, and administrative materials.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_af0250e01a7a1849fdba32940e11d6a5" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>School, 1934-1988 and undated</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_0ebfcad1731a6aa833ef14cfe0088521" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >28</container>
        </did>
        <c02 id="aspace_ad3be5993ed5225b1aa6e0d744c7fafd" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>School Administration, 1947-1977</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_761efd609cdae08a7b3c962afccfd08d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">28</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_a541419536117128431e18e5924e13c0" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Academic Credit, 1948-1977 and undated</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">31
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_732a481d5b285d370c95faab63b73e8f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">28</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_517de4dbcc7c45d414baa40dcf4d429d">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains letters of interest, correspondence, notes, student lists, credit
                explanations, form letters, and administrative materials that address ADF's policies
                and practices toward academic credit in relation to ADF courses. Records address
                Connecticut College students receiving academic credit for ADF courses, inquiries
                from other academic institutions about ADF's course work, and inquiries from
                students regarding academic credit. Also includes correspondence initiated by ADF
                with similar summer dance schools and programs regarding academic credit.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_15ff4b91d172d14fc50a11f7a14200e3" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Administration, 1947-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.75 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_bd6a5f07fc50d313b4ef5b7cc68ccbba" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">28</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_8a1f13697004c5fcbde424e711b83145">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains ADF School administrative materials such as information about school
                policies, procedures, programs, and student application and registration, forms and
                form letters, letters of interest from prospective students and faculty,
                correspondence with faculty and students unable to attend, information about mass
                mailings, schedules for classes (working copies), master calendars, weekly status
                reports about school applicants, correspondence, and notes. Subseries is organized
                chronologically with categories within each year. Items of interest include
                correspondence with faculty unable to attend, such as Mary Wigman (1951), Anna
                Halprin (1958), Merce Cunningham (1962), Norman and Ruth Lloyd (1962), Eleo Pomare
                (1965), and Martha Graham (1968).</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_3e33ea037ec893e9e16b45e30079f6d8" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1947-1959</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_5a41a699be9a0fa9e1e774efb5072638" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">28</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_0f38c4dda6050deafe75b415894b91e8" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1960-1970</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_ab37973c290affa9b65586bff3f29df9" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">29</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_a7b9586e0057adf6bbad2de69a533d9c" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1971-1977 and undated</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_25d08106fa6403ee68c2bea2a6bd8cc0" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">30</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_c5fe9c6bdbd1e979d86b28ed526e55d3" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Advisory Board, 1956-1973</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_b112cff121b977c7452c0207f05fdde9" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">31</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_47088ab276b173c149540782e9b87120">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, agenda, meeting minutes, and notes pertaining to the
                planning of the ADF School and the upcoming season. The Advisory Board, in
                conjunction with the Festival Committee, was the decision-making body for nearly all
                activities of the School of Dance and the Festival season including faculty,
                accompanists, workshops, scholarships and scholarship winners, the dates of the
                school, and special projects. The Board also made decisions about funding and
                administrative personnel.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d630223b3e8735eddb065b591e87f157" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Dance Costumes, 1948-1969</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">14
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_f93d3f60a078375cbe437f5c2b8ea463" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">31</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_5a5d07f01afe8176576c94cc99dff551">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence between the ADF School and Wright and Ditson, a dance
                clothing supply house, discussing the styles and colors of the regulation costume,
                consisting of a choice of leotard and tights, required by the ADF School. Also
                includes Wright and Ditson order forms and notices to students about their dance
                attire.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d81cefc98afed1d3fb3d7528fa9c9653" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Dance Medicine and Infirmary, 1948-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">15
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_32bc10b4eed803c5cce4bd5d77ed3ef4" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">31</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_fe0327a93d776653025c0ecc330e8265">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains statistical reports of ailments and injuries treated by the Connecticut
                College infirmary, correspondence between ADF and Connecticut College regarding
                usage of the infirmary during the summer, and general information about the
                infirmary hours and emergency contacts for students.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_02cfd48b363ff49bf7c7403a0ed02406" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Housing, Meals, and Car Registration, 1948-1977 and undated</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_848e0c900c596925ddede51bf3be3f0e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">31</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_02a233216d86dc8dadbbdfb791cc8e7a">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains housing and dining room lists, dormitory floor plans, correspondence,
                forms, housing meeting minutes, meal tickets, notes regarding housing preferences
                and decisions, and car registration forms. Also includes completed questionnaires or
                information from local residents who rented their homes to members of the ADF
                community.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_6b04280e72f0e2224ce9c5c8ecb01bff" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Recruitment, 1961-1974 and undated</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_528e06eb08070654a471e3f8d01b6ebc" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">31</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_7fe4ff4377c850c850e960f4d10969dc">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains materials, such as mailing lists of college dance departments and forms
                for a traveling ADF School photo exhibit, concerning the recruitment of students for
                the school.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_22b3bb4bf245b4e379bc486fbad204e7" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Curriculum, 1934-1977</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_6421e628b35ef6a00ff33f1da66c8477" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">32</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_c013742b65100fdcd47356009207ac93" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Bulletins and Catalogs, 1934-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">33
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_8a5adc6dc25be894c1395c890d756f94" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">32</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e5ead4795935b475642cbfd6eaf74ccf">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains school catalogs or bulletins listing faculty, classes, and other school
                information. Drafts of the catalogs and bulletins, proof copies, or administrative
                materials concerning the creation or printing of catalogs and bulletins are filed in
                Administration under the Publications Office series.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f4e80db32f8d16293c1c3cf81f507768" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Children's Classes, 1950-1969</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">17
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_910a96d90eb942ba78e09cfd2133e440" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">32</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_9e4251c70fddd0a964ec12db6e5b3c54">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, forms and form letters, class lists, applications, and
                course materials relating to classes for children (under 12) at Connecticut College
                for young non-residential students. Children's classes were distinct from the ADF's
                community classes offered by the Community Outreach Program and the program was
                known alternately as the Young Dancers Workshop and the Childrens Dance Workshop.
                Teachers included Ruth Ferguson, Harriet Berg, Bonnie Bird, and Virginia Tanner.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_557d4ad82c72b155d0319cb3247b02c7" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Class Auditions, 1967-1976</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">10
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_17ac5a84224ddf1188b25def4609c060" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">32</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_16213b1fd91214fc3237a5a1e2e64709">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains audition lists and audition schedules relating to required group auditions
                held for technique class placement at the beginning of the summer term. Also
                includes correspondence, notes, schedules, and procedure lists for arranging and
                holding auditions.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a846b55555f7f4aafee52e842f06467b" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Class Schedules, 1938-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_0c7b86bb72cf7cc430ae6f7fdb115a78" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">32</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_bb4650a49d1a0ed48fb98ca38d6f3ded">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains tentative and final printed schedules of classes offered during the summer
                session.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_0c147dd2470aee3febf80fa83f6a4f0b" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Courses, 1948-1977 and undated</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_368ebd8432d8d9ab221b9c7a0365f584" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">32</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_867007f7aa8e7adfa8192739fbea6457">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains information about various courses and special workshops, including course
                descriptions, teachers' and students' notes, syllabi, blank exams, handouts, and
                handbooks.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically and arranged alphabetically within each year by course
                title.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_5a36909cc206f031398f9aef43d32ece" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1948-1970</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_7b1a3bd0d43236c24f8287863825b6bc" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">32</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ccf1cf6f6bb34aef37dd1ccfa0624feb" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1971-1977 and undated</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_0550fe71473fa8fb7a0734d62f3c62dd" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">33</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5ac0ee09b73142c2b037f5187bc29e61" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Development, 1949-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">17
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_b09c6394133f9f2faa49fb899a6aa181" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">33</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_80fe710e23ea8f207482ed5c0af889be">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains memoranda, correspondence, minutes, and notes recording discussions,
                meetings, and suggestions about the development of the school as a whole and its
                curricula, faculty, and quality of applicants. Also included are correspondence and
                curriculum proposals by Bessie Schonberg. Of interest are the 1967-1968 proposals of
                a Master of Arts in Dance with a teaching emphasis or a Master of Arts in Fine Arts
                through the ADF School. Also of interest are the notes on the development of the
                Theater Component (1976) and Weekend Workshops (1977).</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_5652dec1d0102acc745df5ef5fe576d8" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Informal Showings, 1948-1975</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_ba4adf2caed9520c95686cbb61206cbc" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">33</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_697a45571001bc3ee71b404996d7a6bc">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains programs, program materials, memoranda, correspondence, and sign-up sheets
                regarding informal performances of student choreography, improvisation, and movement
                studies. Class Showings were informal programs of specific classes, performed by
                students and reflecting their "in progress" work developed during their daily
                classes. Student Workshops were informal weekly performances, and approximately six
                were presented during a summer session. Student Concerts were informal performances
                of student-choreographed compositions performed by students.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically and within each year arranged into categories of Class
                Showings, Student Concerts, and Student Workshops.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_b44b8d5794c3e9e200e919dffffaf063" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Posters, 1949-1968</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_1da79ce7ade307e9eddc8d02f32076f1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">33</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a09dfa2fa56fe2367fb3cb2d3e9b2106">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains posters advertising the school curriculum and faculty.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_444b73e6926c1a70bb095412cb6a4280" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Posters, 1959, 1961, 1963, 1967, 1968</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_b9901205eea60b84ba0e89521a5cf116" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">OS2</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_4ebd35d43a0bd5928b2761b639b13ba3">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains posters advertising the school curriculum and faculty.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_68bf676303bde511aaf9efdfdd087c57" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Special and Master Classes, 1971-1974</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_bea2b9347189f6568c7f826498649d81" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">33</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_30b9501dc7b75dce6e53397281c2e1d8">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains sign-up sheets, schedules, and flyers advertising special and master
                classes that were offered in addition to the regular course offerings as a one-time
                opportunity for students to receive instruction from visiting dance artists,
                including Rudy Perez, Louis Falco, and Murray Louis.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_b735d74714e354fff8c36de4e830d66e" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Workshops for Professionals, 1953-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.58 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_c1bca1378ac355808917c4640d7fa11d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">33</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_17f958ed4c974017936d17666243bd85">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, course materials, printed materials, letters of interest,
                and student papers and evaluations pertaining to workshops held for dance and
                movement educators and dance accompanists. These were special "refresher" or
                "intensive" workshops tailored specifically for professionals in the dance field who
                were dance or movement teachers, dance accompanists, or dance therapists. Workshop
                instructors included Delia Hussey, Ruth Murray, Barbara Beiswanger, Theodora
                Wiesner, Bonnie Bird, Marion North, and Virginia Tanner.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a34c01bf9a36530915ef2e0d19905bcd" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Dean of the School (Martha Myers), 1968-1988 and undated</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_e3d9435495f76f45ffe62d7e3fee128a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">34</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_7d9945e9146836d4b041e0284393269b">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, recommendation letters, and notes relating to Myers'
                activities associated with the school and with her professional activities at
                Connecticut College and in the dance world.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_56ee1d5fd12561c2e0a91d1e2dc7f740" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Faculty, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_349f7d94643be22a9cdb94e31b7995fb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">34</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_cdb14e4f2eeca81ec21333f9eec06cdf" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Appointments, 1948-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">18
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_a62805e1765d405a3234d1514e3f5a57" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">34</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_5570801969c60ec3d1ee02873764ea74">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains lists of teaching faculty, faculty assistants, and accompanists. Lists may
                contain information such as biographical blurbs or informal salary and expense
                information.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_99e157b2fdceee6da42b474581dcde79" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Faculty Files, 1948-1977 and undated</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4.25 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_ef2bf342a96cf1b780f1852bd82cedec" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">34</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_961975dcca8d34701669856ae3f1644c">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, contracts, housing forms, notes, memos to individual
                faculty members, and recommendations regarding teaching faculty, teaching
                assistants, accompanists, and workshop directors (Dance Educators, Dance Therapy,
                and Dance Accompanists). Also includes some biographical materials and some
                materials regarding ADF classes. Several faculty members played multiple roles at
                the festival (e.g. performer, workshop director, faculty member). Materials relating
                to the individual roles a participant played will be filed by the subject of the
                materials. For example, Helen Priest Rogers' correspondence about the Film and
                Notation project is filed in the Special Projects subgroup, and her correspondence
                relating to plans for teaching a Labanotation course will be filed in the Faculty
                Files. Her course materials, such as syllabi and handouts, is filed in Courses in
                the Curriculum subseries. Materials regarding faculty who were invited but could not
                attend and letters of interest from potential faculty members are filed in the
                School Administration series under Administration.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically and within each year alphabetically by surname of faculty
                member.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <bioghist id="aspace_db5f3d363f37ddf8da5dd4c46513368d">
              <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
              <p>From 1948 through the mid to late 1960s, ADF's faculty consisted of a core group of
                teachers, many of whom were also involved as regular festival performers and
                advisors to the festival and the school including Martha Graham, Jose and Pauline
                Limon, Doris Humphrey, Louis Horst, William Bales, Helen Priest Rogers, George and
                Barbara Beiswanger, Norman and Ruth Lloyd, Hazel Johnson, and George McGeary. ADF
                Directors Ruth Bloomer and Theodora Wiesner also taught during this period. Other
                faculty of note from this period are Alwin Nikolais, Murray Louis, Alvin Ailey,
                Donald McKayle, Glenn Mack, Jane Dudley, Sophie Maslow, Betty Jones, Ruth Currier,
                Doris Rudko, David and Marnie Wood, Martha and Josef Wittman, Lucas Hoving, Daniel
                Nagrin, Pauline Koner, Bessie Schonberg, and Yuriko. Later faculty included Walter
                Nicks, Meredith Monk, Arthur Hall, Anna Halprin, Peter Saul, and Mel Wong.</p>
            </bioghist>
            <c04 id="aspace_952f5d2c95b85481f3b0ae73f609a64b" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1948-1958</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_bb44f477230c6bd2e2ba304b0106ee01" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">34</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_420938c7df034c0820114679f6e8bc10" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1959-1965</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_ef06dbaa0f7260164d01a992a85d5157" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">35</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_339abc8552114b6d5a2df82955f876ab" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1966-1973</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_6119b5a70147175b53d4c99fee1bb538" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">36</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_13e6da368d47d47c263b881590d5a1dc" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1974-1977 and undated</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_977a94b397554299f1d46f7ecc8603e9" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">37</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_477ca02e06af28d37bf77f0d348cab6e" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Evaluations, circa 1956-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">17
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_cf62a1c3f4d452a7e5ab311bedbc9d73" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">37</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_e7b84159204e3ecb3c0f007af76c234a">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, notes, and evaluation forms from faculty members on the
                previous season and their recommendations for the next year's school and
                festival.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_cc59b99d1751a32a4a6c41d62c14a0b3" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Memos to Faculty, circa 1948-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">36
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_01815349d6c6bb98979230f5f7fe72b3" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">37</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_374d8f909658c352469e46ec9f3f30c0">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains memos sent to faculty members and advisors as a group, not to individuals.
                Individual correspondence and memos sent to faculty members are filed in Faculty
                Files. Memos include announcements regarding class grades and credits, scheduling
                classes, tentative class schedules for faculty review, advising students, student
                registration, the season's teaching faculty and school, visitors and guests at the
                festival, complimentary tickets, housing and meals, and invitations to faculty
                meetings and social gatherings. In the 1970s, memos were often sent out as packets
                to faculty members before they arrived for the season.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_28c53116a1eebff27764a9ecc1ff2d0a" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Meetings, circa 1949-1975</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">20
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_8989698cc04c07032675310ed117fac1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">37</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_f117536d0a97e111ee9e0ff6db4a2f60">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains agenda and meeting minutes of faculty meetings. Minutes exist as unedited
                drafts, handwritten and typed notes, and final copies that were distributed to the
                faculty or to the Director and Dean.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4b6b96bad9a9568d2b1e979c4c767ae5" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Students, 1939-1977 and undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_dad1bd16ca631d304257b0d7501268c6" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">38</container>
          </did>
          <c03 id="aspace_4a09f4a4628a86eb086b3cc79c076d99" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Class Lists, 1948-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_d5892b5c79e98ee8e9d5e504c8e08c0b" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">38</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_ec7245a69139ee70a653e282510a3397">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains lists of students who participated in classes at the ADF School,
                equivalent to attendance sheets or grade sheets. Grades are frequently on the class
                lists or grade books included.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically and within each year by the surname of faculty
                member.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_f9cf16433317e09f6472a301432f30c9" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Enrollment, 1939-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.42 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_c1563ca0ae3afca30c9dfa7a39a1a00c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">39</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_a76be6118ab1f4f981e47ea5908994d7">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains administrative enrollment lists and statistics regarding acceptance and
                enrollment in the ADF School and enrollment in individual classes and workshops
                (though not Special Project workshops). Also contains administrative information
                about class drop/adds.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_74ddc00a4b4d69c7ce904cc4f3570b94" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Evaluations and Surveys, 1948-1976</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.42 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_4962dc2792fa690a006b5afc1157599e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">39</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_0f3cd7eac7d8e84daade409f092263b6">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains completed student evaluation forms and administrative compilations of
                evaluations quoting students' reactions on their experiences as members of the ADF
                School. Also contains limited correspondence from students evaluating their
                experiences. Most evaluations are anonymous. May also include faculty evaluations
                where the author could not be distinguished as faculty or student.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_466847949c3e16f446b59feafc17565c" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>General Information, 1948-1977 and undated</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.25 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_c594d2969a866764b5cf22f268a1118a" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">39</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_2b538b23d8d3a2fc3735ac8e06737e24">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains printed material, such as memos, schedules, forms, and information sheets,
                generated by the ADF School and disseminated to all students. Topics include
                registration, classes, housing, cafeteria, recreation, and other information
                relating to the student's life on campus.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_93ec2ea17011d9d269c1b68421b59885" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>G.I. Bill, 1948-1967</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">6
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_bedd93810836f9d8df85817c1341d039" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">39</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_2136fe6c4274c640fae8304a6e85fe78">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains correspondence, letters of interest, official materials and information
                from the Veterans Administration, and applications of accepted G.I. Bill of Rights
                students who could not attend. Correspondence in this subseries is largely between
                Connecticut College officials and School of the Dance Directors regarding procedures
                for attending the School of the Dance on the GI Bill.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_9998290e0bc250513320ead53be02d1c" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Handbooks and Packets, 1938-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_981cab8143df936dc139a9bbf4a61300" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">39</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_5769ea2d526b9b8d2b70c05b176db384">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains handbooks or packets for ADF School students. Handbooks and packets
                contain general information compiled to orient students about the school, the
                festival, and the college where the school was held.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d95261c1baace327cf1aece8aee94ab1" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Other Activities, 1951-1971</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_3b53dbb17665984d5e170f9e197ebfe0" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">39</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_5695bc3113c648a96e3f898e38c69b9b">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains memos, flyers, and correspondence concerning activities and excursions
                organized by ADF for the students outside the curriculum and the ADF School,
                including square dances, special films, and trips to Mystic Seaport and to other
                attractions in the surrounding region.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d324b268ce9190acf275d09d7f837faa" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Scholarships and Financial Aid, 1948-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.5 Linear
                  Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_2a6f1547572198f1f1d2ddd01674b409" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">40</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_7b98f0c2c1224606dc77998aa2a81330">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains administrative documents and correspondence related to publicizing and
                arranging scholarships and financial aid for ADF School applicants, including forms
                and form letters, letters of interest from students about specific scholarships, all
                applications for the Doris Humphrey Fellow (except for the winner, whose materials
                are filed in her student record), and a sampling of student records of students who
                either applied for or were awarded financial aid (scholarships particularly) but
                were unable to attend. All correspondence relating to individual students who
                attended the School and received scholarships is filed in the Student Records
                subseries. Notable documents include letters of recommendation from Mary Wigman
                (1958), Martha Graham (1963), and Arthur Mitchell (1974).</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically and then into the following subject categories:
                Apprenticeships and Assistantships, Cooperative Scholarships, Doris Humphrey
                Fellowships, Foreign Scholarships, Ruth Bloomer Loan Fund, and Scholarships.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c04 id="aspace_c85a59571f3e4c600029b6de4b99dd99" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1948-1965</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_06c0a98f905b7e027f6c72aadb5e190b" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">40</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_9dbff6602994b992bb1b2dff6f2359b6" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1966-1977</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_3670f9bb42599f3f0aad813e16a2a223" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">41</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_13c78b2590efcf6faf670dd4ca8e48bf" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Student Records, 1939-1977</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">33.75
                  Linear Feet</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_8e05cb97f5ecb26280f07435c20867eb" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">42</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_b9679c725eb8d041773e493da6174688">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains student records for the Six-Week School, the Four-Week School for Young
                Dancers, participants in workshops such as Dance Educators and Dance Therapy,
                members of the Theatre Component, Doris Humphrey Fellows and all scholarship and
                financial aid students, faculty and staff members who took one or two classes, and
                part-time students. Not included are participants in Community Workshops, Special
                Projects, or Children's Classes.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically and then alphabetically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <userestrict id="aspace_8c041488baeed0cca813987c5401c3ce">
              <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
              <p>RESTRICTED: In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974
                as amended, the American Dance Festival Archives permits students to inspect their
                education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information
                from education records. During the life of the student, access to others is
                restricted without written permission from the student.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <c04 id="aspace_f8a470b5a745190c364143b47807ddf5" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1939, 1940, 1948-1951</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_0f2e6db960bbe1bb4ca9d544882f5613" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">42</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_f64c3c27472cc0bb188f722524730034" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1952, 1953</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_e9444c0c4663d1e27eba0439ba6c4317" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">43</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_d0f7c0a71b6ed34dd4061b1369acfbda" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1954, 1955 A-L</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_634c2dc175bff9bb37860d5e01cdd79f" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">44</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_0452c9fe44f36626e7dc3aad45732eca" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1955 M-Z, 1956</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_4d4a8fa87dfb618fbca332fed2b62715" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">45</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_949487d42412b0364c074eeff916f13a" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1957, 1958 A-P</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_fe43f3e4453aa6de25182dea4ac924a3" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">46</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_a2dc4ce58a9d83be0342165e34d6491e" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1958 Q-Z, 1959</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_c0f118c7a5222372462e4e934cf68922" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">47</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_1d3c7da33b4f9cf403f4856a0ad565bc" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1960</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_16da674e4ed8da40082609d3e593ca42" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">48</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_9a437e4b55da8b436a8403149318ab03" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1961</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_22bf21b632b632655e21ccb78baf00e8" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">49</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_ecf70ed6e4c6cab8b635a43870a37783" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1962, 1963 A-B</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_8885141f1785e5fb1727902992996ee8" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">50</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_04f8d5ff83e2d87a353c034f762b4a72" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1963 C-Z, 1964 A-J</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_c117beeec1c700651b8fa43024f445c2" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">51</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_af63844162729ad079dc7eea23bba599" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1964 K-Z, 1965 A-L</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_8ef358d2904934df38d9edafded63225" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">52</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_653d0527baec29b136e1a049e0db3178" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1965 M-Z, 1966 A-J</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_45d8a20728b8474b7595d79471e92042" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">53</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_893ada942ae42162983835f33f990b48" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1966 K-Z, 1967 A-R</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_5249099464283e826cc29712f90d4cea" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">54</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_d9a049fe4a297f26640d2504413b87cc" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1967 S-Z, 1968, 1969 A-E</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_f34410d4bf88d83cc007e39d415641f2" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">55</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_0a09d42498c1a2cd411769679f2ffd4a" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1969 F-Z</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_3386695b2af5a694d8ae2d19fade3895" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">56</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_bf854125401b39ea227b0f781bb7dcc5" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1970 A-R</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_367f85fbbcba9306a76c8bd5d4e72901" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">57</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_2d9e031521a47df38795ce0543e2edda" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1970 S-Z, 1971 A-K</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_312c73c9e6279c10ee1e05239b2110b9" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">58</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_488c38849d068907d0d200a0afdc0a70" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1971 L-Z, 1972 A-B</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_b4220cb8c1cd5bb44071fd3cae018afe" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">59</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_a83f8ca9fcd982f4d8820b227bf5c9ad" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1972 C-R</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_ea8786f917ea923700fc38769068243a" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">60</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_492078963f693809a523f619417ca139" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1972 S-Z, 1973 A-H</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_4b3ea49068370b787309994f688c11be" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">61</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_474fc8ed2d30a743995b5e4f998f9909" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1973 H-Z , 1974 A-G</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_cc49b4e6a4b4ea2334046baee0f550f0" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">62</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_55c05961ba463cf1eac688fda878845c" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1974 H-Sc</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_25df5989894d7a46cb439e3fa312687e" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">63</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_7d16f6e7986c18fc9c47d2bce9c057e7" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1974 Se-Z, 1975 A-K</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_67ed46be09bd439e1e34c07bf1ab8c2c" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">64</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_792c84faa66b20b3966b5cac4ab4e9eb" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1975 L-V</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_f8cc976b1e6bba7ecd930700beaa53c1" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">65</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_5470aa1760839dcfcc54845fe7f72d96" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1975 W-Z, 1976 A-Nel</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_024ac64cf8edb6fb891462f5ad1cfea4" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">66</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_fde14eed33b66b01350d2aae908c95b1" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1976 New-Z, 1977 A-Bra</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_4f7b12ecf4ad3c2370ee8ec1657dd335" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">67</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 id="aspace_59c357318ed86e1b04e31d58378d4979" level="file">
              <did>
                <unittitle>1977 Bre-Z</unittitle>
                <container id="aspace_a717fa8b0ef12345cf46077466ea8d4e" label="Mixed Materials"
                  type="box">68</container>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d2b53435e3dafb210d478267622236a2" level="subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Young Choreographers, 1959-1967</unittitle>
              <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9
                  folders</extent></physdesc>
              <container id="aspace_76609e099a3f981fbe3d50c11306d399" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">69</container>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_89611b488c0ea96f9894d2adaaeadf82">
              <head>Scope and Contents</head>
              <p>Contains audition sign-up sheets, audition rating sheets, memos, notes,
                correspondence, and programs pertaining to Young Choreographers' Concerts held
                during the summer session as a main stage performance. Participants in the Young
                Choreographers' auditions appear to be mostly students, but other participants were
                up-and-coming dancers who were not current students at the school. Auditioners and
                finalists include Trisha Brown (1962), Meredith Monk (1963), Martha Clarke (1962),
                Betty Jones (1960), Lar Lubovitch (1962), Carla Maxwell (1965), and Senta Driver
                (1965). The Young Choreographers' Concerts were active during the 1960s and are not
                related to the Young Choreographers and Composers program, 1983-1995.</p>
              <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
            </scopecontent>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_eb7ea72e38269b282f31acf883b98725" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>General Correspondence, circa 1948-1977</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">28
              folders</extent></physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_6c3080268587653c9a03f46e5682a2a6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >69</container>
        </did>
        <arrangement id="aspace_a26d76541c13996cba5adfd228460104">
          <head>Arrangement</head>
          <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_6bbb5eb7664301585d6c00bb78adb915">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Contains correspondence between audience and participants and ADF members. Materials
            include correspondence from audience members writing to express appreciation or
            unhappiness regarding ADF presentations and inquiries regarding programs, school
            visitation, and local accommodations. Series also includes congratulatory letters and
            telegrams from ADF personnel and students and personal letters to the directors
            regarding administrative details and personal appreciation for the festival. In
            addition, there are miscellaneous form letters to the community such as a 1951 form
            letter inviting local artists to sketch dance classes.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_db32bd654bd762922353d8319f9d0909" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Printed Material, 1930-1977</unittitle>
          <container id="aspace_62a9dae2b9c08189e5d92829acfc33f6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >69</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_48ac7fbff597cf8b8fd2a2d7bd800f50">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Contains most printed materials created by ADF. Some printed materials are in other
            series. For example, school catalogs are under School, Curriculum, Bulletins and
            Catalogs.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_a067823ba0b6f5548bed4a1b78b0c2c3" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Advertisements, 1949-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_e1e0dab704ece3f8a922304a76395f40" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">69</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_ed72b9fd05a2db9741b2f03c78b60e71">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains ADF marketing materials for the school, festival performances, and special
              projects held during the summer festival, including brochures, newspaper inserts,
              handbills, and advertisements printed in newspapers and magazines. Also includes some
              Connecticut College materials, Connecticut and New England educational and tourism
              brochures, and national dance publications in which ADF placed advertisements.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_48c6f96540f2429011d6185429df1c07" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>ADF Publications, 1948-1967</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">27
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_025b14a0baa65e93c2dfc5b0f780d265" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">69</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_0ef6468a564cffaaa2a25e7cf58943e2">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains ADF published items including booklets and newsletters.</p>
            <p> Arranged alphabetically by title.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_607414676a16852db66be2a8297ecea0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="italic" xlink:type="simple">Dance Advance</title>, 1948-1963
                (13 folders)</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_3b70fcbb8ef4abb7241cd93b5b300438" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">69</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_335a4dff09f71def19c2d932dcf5d5b4" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="italic" xlink:type="simple">A Decade of Dance:
                  1948-1957</title></unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_5941851cc06bf1acd25b673189348801" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">69</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_a3951853bb475b0880d3ada92d7035a7" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="italic" xlink:type="simple">Footprints</title>,
                1967</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_6a20fc4c24e14d6ac56e25c7b5e01e1f" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">69</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_663811548720de62f5b9f17823e5d387" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle><title render="doublequote" xlink:type="simple">Nike on the Campus</title>,
                circa 1967</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_c51a37637b0b38a566a171045cbaf7c1" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">69</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5b8405ac28825c29a3f9c16c048b5da4" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>ADF Information, 1936-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">24
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_58b0ff8374943bac005dd272c9b732bd" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">69</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1b929cc286634de447376122a209b52f">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains materials that provide information about the school and festival in
              narrative, list, and statistical formats, including narrative materials about ADF's
              history, descriptions of special project programs that developed during the 1970s,
              lists of choreographic works and premieres performed at ADF, documentation of opening
              and closing dates for the ADF School, a listing of students who achieved recognition
              in the dance field, and fact sheets. The information from these documents was often
              used for publicity or grant-writing purposes.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_d90c485714179cb78c27ede2a47a6b75" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Bibliographies and Catalogs, 1930-1974 and undated</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.33 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_eed1501556c10c33d898e5378a800d2d" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">69</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_d008da76025fca995167628c78d49746">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains dance and music bibliographies and dance film and costume catalogs. Most of
              the bibliographies were compiled for student and ADF community usage during the ADF
              School. In some years, Connecticut College compiled a "Library Reporter" bibliography
              of dance books especially for the ADF School during the summer. Other bibliographies
              may have been compiled by ADF faculty for summer courses at the ADF School or by ADF
              directors in their own teaching endeavors. Catalogs represent a sampling of film,
              music, and costume catalogs that ADF used to order literature or costume for courses
              or special film series and lectures.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4e401045cbc3042131f4b01572ca2d3c" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Directories and Mailing Lists, 1937-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_78ecf666f878fbd70e91a806403c7725" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">69</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1c568346d6d6d199cd5f4dac45e6e5f2">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains phone and address directories for participants in the ADF School, workshops,
              and performances, as well as faculty and staff members. Most years contain directories
              for both home and summer (at ADF) addresses and phone numbers, and most all
              directories identify the individual's occupation.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_8d3d7aeb6d1dbaf8b0d9701ef7248a8a" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1937-1952</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_e93e7e3ad10a58645069a7ec841d4fb6" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">69</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d3f87918436e5d68ae1d1a4b16a981d8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1953-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_75812f07cbdfe042ba89bb8b011b6a5c" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">70</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_5fb1f277c14229618c96957d09c77736" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Ephemera, 1957-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_3be903f4ce9b6437568dbfb1a09502a8" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">70</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_b4a88718185e371fbf3d76ec0dcbbb3f">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains student meal tickets, identification cards, ADF letterhead, small flyers
              circulated to advertise the performance season, and a sampling of materials generated
              by the Friends' organization in New London.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_f6877a6464615f6630b6ce42dd7e3568" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Invitations, 1958-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_6cd8082b8acfbda096e711e88a619bcd" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">70</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_3ae6e85cd184cb0071e4aec34eb243bb">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains invitations issued by ADF to various members of the ADF community, such as
              faculty, staff, performers, students, as well as members of the Connecticut College
              staff and potential donors. Types of events include open houses, opening parties at
              the beginning of the season, post-performance parties and receptions, brunches,
              cocktail receptions, lecture demonstrations, and performances.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_4d8231d23528170ffc384680d3492bf4" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Labanotation, 1954-1977 and undated</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">12
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_6efc8aeb7c802ba5902172ac4de8f1bb" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">70</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_87f0ae9e993fddacee34a8e11261d66c">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains press releases, scores, textbooks, correspondence, and notes referring to
              Labanotation.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_891c88349087418ae7e71e5a642859a0" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Mailers and Brochures, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">30
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_3f1b404d9d8cd6ae847f671e4f6c52be" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">70</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_ed02d229a5d03eed3babedc62ea42922">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains printed materials sent to members of the ADF community, prospective
              students, and potential ticket buyers, including performance and school announcements,
              schedules of performances, ticket order forms, informational brochures, schedules and
              calendars, school bulletins and catalogs, and advertising flyers and posters that were
              sent through the mail. Form letters are not included in this series.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_da1daf5c43596766c5cd56c84e2082d5" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1948-1962</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_a6a5bf7da6227e2b806854f45b65adc2" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">70</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_055819d05b68856b747fee0041ca0ad4" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1963-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_5a332876a5399291cf5ce1a43d7c591e" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">71</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_68a7d3e8f8250da5fed631bdc51245e6" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Playbills, 1950, 1952, 1956, 1964-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">17
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_b0982dde27f82fe3ea9f031e81a04c5e" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">71</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_1540b170588b678ba59b0a69afb7e3aa">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Playbills contain artist information, school and festival information, and
              advertisements.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_10bedb7644d4cf39040b4d13749483a9" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Posters, 1954, 1959-1968</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">9
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_83236667e355792d9342738399b94e44" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">71</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_734dc8cd26a69861a09c8016fabef7b8">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_2ad60f60530faecc836bb277cd94b476" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Posters, 1959-1960, 1962-1964, 1966-1974, 1976</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_eb5ad45c49f6175411b5582e4dca7797" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">OS2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_119d688c306aefd69e264ef60713c7dc" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Programs, 1934-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.0 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_1997943bdbe2cec43808e0f8b627e3f9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">71</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_68723c9d4afd6189c6612138be2db677">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_91b8c95c7c90860da9d856c0ab66bfa8" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1934-1960</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_275569beb2e3a9e8e1eaabec4123c5f2" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">71</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_d7a3eec893a0ef8e9aa3b176df9deb4d" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1961-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_07d499ac567e39aa0b3d5a3376fa5204" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">72</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_4904bf920e9c34b4fec853876c653feb" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>Two volumes of bound programs, 1958-1966</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_0d8107bd0ceee3b0409f2157fa3fc706" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">73</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_1ac8109b97191a848ead36bbe59ef7fa" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Season Reports and Statistics, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.5 Linear
                Feet</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_2f453a164087031ebcd1e3f8f44d18c2" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">72</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_48bc7b30d87791fed00eb9d92415d0c0">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains narrative and statistical reports of both the ADF School and festival
              performances. School statistics include enrollment numbers, average ages of students,
              and their geographical distribution. </p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
          <c03 id="aspace_6b73e5ba3d756b98b9439e2f4f19e169" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1948-1963</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_ad97675efe6c071d382d716c00066a7d" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">72</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 id="aspace_779849d59b9793a45d077d0bb95bd7d0" level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle>1964-1977</unittitle>
              <container id="aspace_8322589a4aae11b8301849bb04854f25" label="Mixed Materials"
                type="box">74</container>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_26f52815cfe72f42fd9be99cfdc563ed" level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Schedules and Calendars, 1948-1977</unittitle>
            <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">30
                folders</extent></physdesc>
            <container id="aspace_ed4f25e1dbc5e9f42219d40471c00c81" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">74</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent id="aspace_7623bafdc52fd4bf248f3a943ef848bf">
            <head>Scope and Contents</head>
            <p>Contains schedules and calendars circulated internally among the ADF students,
              faculty, and performers, and publicly to members of the ADF community and prospective
              students and ticket buyers. Includes schedules and calendars of performances, ticket
              order forms, school schedules, opening week schedules, weekly schedules, meal
              schedules, schedules of events open to the public, and lecture series schedules.</p>
            <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_da82cc7042bbf3573696243b24ba39d6" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Awards and Tributes, 1959-1974 and undated</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">13
              folders</extent></physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_817afa54a33d0aa3bc2726f15f7fa04c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >74</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_ead7a24fdbe27126711fae0f2a1909e2">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Contains correspondence informing interested parties of the death of Ruth Bloomer,
            donations to the scholarship fund established in her honor, and acknowledgements of
            these donations, correspondence regarding the loss of Doris Humphrey and materials
            regarding a Doris Humphrey memorial program, funding requests and acknowledgements
            regarding the Louis Horst Memorial Fund and the 1964 Louis Horst Memorial Concert,
            materials regarding the 1973 Jose Limon Memorial Film Program, and materials regarding
            the Simon Sadoff Award to acknowledge the contributions and achievements of musical
            conductors in dance.</p>
          <p> Arranged chronologically.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02 id="aspace_836282db0b6983eedf626023f10a7fa5" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Ruth Bloomer Fund and Memorial, 1959</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d0ae6cb841c14b239656dfda781ef24f" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">74</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_a05f0bd45875cb2b3e157b9d2fbd6fa9" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Doris Humphrey, 1959-1960 (3 folders)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_5d42254bc2ac938b492ad7a8763b1bc9" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">74</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_b81c5eebf5289152cd3b1c6045ca71d2" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Louis Horst, 1961</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_d88f25050e0d747b4827d8fd26ce0d57" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">74</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_1e8596cf782b89b9d2d86ff54006f1b0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Louis Horst, 1964 (4 folders)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_0e0c562c6659b44254dd00e012c94fb7" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">74</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_1241888be8f23b0b2da3efd26ceb1d96" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Jose Limon, 1972-1973 (2 folders)</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_aece33fb5333174263ab4af19129e305" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">74</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_dfb9cad00612e45ae4a53dcbde83eaf0" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Simon Sadoff, 1974</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_766649670aed1610dc32d2b471bc7e98" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">74</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 id="aspace_2652895649394d7afcf93604cffb5b42" level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Ruth Bloomer, undated</unittitle>
            <container id="aspace_ecfdfffb7f44a1d71744944579475741" label="Mixed Materials"
              type="box">74</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 id="aspace_f4a9574d34c36acd74276cd395b98c33" level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Other Organizations, 1942-1977</unittitle>
          <physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.42 Linear
              Feet</extent></physdesc>
          <container id="aspace_efd77d9b68f01d121ddb07797392aa64" label="Mixed Materials" type="box"
            >74</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_5bf5006687c25a93066d40f050b76303">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Contains printed materials concerning organizations with parallel or related activities
            (e.g., Jacob's Pillow and the Dance Notation Bureau).</p>
          <p> Arranged alphabetically.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
